<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->


<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Marie</title>
	<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se</link>
	<description>Developer, Role player, Idealist</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 12:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://mariehogebrandt.se</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://mariehogebrandt.se</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[marie]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[iam@mariehogebrandt.se]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Marie]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Marie]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Hogebrandt]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[webmaster]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[webmistress@melindrea.net]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[webmaster]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	

	<item>
		<title>Last Wish</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/last-wish/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 18:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=17</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="story">Full story</h2>

<h3 id="childhood">A budding priestess</h3>

<p>She is born to a robber, Wandering Moon, who's partner, Brilliant Frost, was killed when they were caught. Her mother found out in captivity that she was pregnant, and pleaded that even if she could not live, her child had done nothing wrong. Of course, in the Haslanti League, having another mouth to feed can sometimes kill the entire family, but a kindly wandering disciple of Kilidos named Morning's Joy decided to adopt the child. His wife Whispering Sky had died in childbirth a few months prior, and he saw this new life as a way to deal with his own pain and grief. He spent the final months of Wandering Moon's life talking to her about herself and her husband, so that he could tell the child once she was old enough to understand. Only one thing did Wandering Moon beg him to never let the child know: Her fear that Brilliant Frost had already been dead when they conceived. They had been together when the ambush came, and Frost had been shot, dying in her loving arms.</p>

<p>Her adoptive father named her Last Wish, to honour her mother's last wish, and raised her lovingly. They were poor, but never wanted for the most important things in life: Shelter, enough food to stave off starvation, and love. She was happy, and he taught her to not fear death, to always look for the story behind everything, to give what comfort she could. The first few years he stayed in one village, but once she was old enough to join him on his travels, he set off again. They travelled in various directions of the Haslanti League during the warmer months, and spent the cold seasons in whatever village it seemed best to be, guided by his common sense and dreams from Kilidos, who certainly knew a loyal and precious devotee when she saw one.</p>

<h3 id="compassion">Compassion unrivalled</h3>

<p>She was a young teenager when they stayed at the village of Dark's Reach, five days north of Icehome, for the winter. Morning's Joy was a good man, firm but fair, and he was of the opinion that as long as she had finished her duties — and she had quite a few of them — she could do what she wanted to do for fun. She was a fairly lonely child, because although she was friendly and had an easy time to get liked, she rarely cultivated the friendships, knowing fully well that she might never see her new friends again, as they moved on to the next village, the next person who needed comfort. Thus, she found a set of caves a bit outside the village, entertaining herself with climbing and exploring them, until the day when she'd lost track of time. It had already started to darken, and she knew she had to get home. Suddenly a girl in her own age was standing there, glaring at her.</p>

<p>“Go away!” The girl snarled, making Last Wish stumble, and she started to turn, the girl yelling at her to go away, until something in the girl's voice resonated with her. Her voice was griefstrucken, she was in pain, and Last Wish knew that it was her duty to stay and help her, so as kindly as she could she told the girl no. It took a few tries, but eventually the girl calmed down enough so that they could talk.</p>

<p>Her name was Jubilant Sky, and she was sad because she was worried about her little sister. Last Wish didn't ask for too many details on what it was she was worried about, figuring that it was better to not hurry things, but rather asked Sky about other things: The rest of her family, if they'd lived there long… Yes, they had, in generations. Her father had died in an attack by hobgoblins, and a few years later her mother remarried, so the little sister was her half-sister. “And what a sweet little thing,“ Jubilant Sky said with a wistful smile. “Blue eyes, blonde hair. She's really adorable, happy...” They talked for quite a few hours, before Last Wish realised she had to go back. She said she'd be back the following day, and Jubilant Sky smiled, nodding some, before slinking away between the rocks.</p>

<p>When she came back to the house, Morning's Joy was beyond himself, starting to yell at her for having been out all night, but when she started to explain he grew silent and shocked. He asked her for every detail, and obediently she gave them, figuring he'd explain it when he was satisfied, which he did.</p>

<p>Twenty years prior, a young girl by the name of Jubilant Sky had disappeared from the village. She lived with her mother and stepfather, her own father having died in an attack by hobgoblins. Five years after she disappeared, her mother gave birth to her little sister, a happy blue-eyed and blonde little girl. When it dawned on Last Wish what she had met — what she had calmed down! — she started shivering. They both knew she had to find out what Jubilant Sky wanted, so the following night she waited, with Morning's Joy hiding to be there in case things turned ugly. She confronted Jubilant Sky, who at first denied everything, until she started to sob, admitting that she was dead, but she was scared. Her stepfather had killed her after doing things to her he shouldn't have, and now he was looking at her sister in the same way. She just wanted to go home, have her shallow grave be found, and her murderer brought to justice.</p>

<p>And so it was. The last Wish saw of Jubilant Sky was her fading away, surrendering to Lethe, her reasons for clinging onto unlife gone. That was when Last Wish realised that it was not enough to comfort the bereaved and calm the dying. What the world needed was justice, for living and dead alike.</p>

<h3>Hard-boiled detective</h3>

<p><small>— In her own words</small> {#inspector}</p>

<p>“It was a dark, dreary night, many years after I had met Jubilant Sky. I was employed by the city guard of Icehome as an inspector, to investigate subtler disturbances of the peace, and though I did not know it as I stepped into the precinct, that was the day that would change everything. That was the day they first found a woman tortured to death, wearing a blindfold, marked with a glyph on her collarbone. She had been abused in ways most would prefer to not think about, but someone still had to, and that someone was I.”</p>

<p>She pulled a drag of the cigarette in it's ivory holder.</p>

<p>“I hunted him for years. I dug deeper into the psyche of evil than I care to think of, and we were closing in. We found out more of what happened, why he did it, and my heart ached. Ghostly servants, gravegoods in a living form. By marking them through necromantic rituals, they were destined to serve him once he died. And not a single of them had seen him. He blindfolded them, his final words always a soft whisper that they would see his glory when he came to collect them. We found ten women across seven years. Each one discarded. How many did we not find? How many were buried where he could visit them again and again?”</p>

<p>A moment she grew silent, looking out over the frozen landscape, collecting her thoughts, forcing herself to be calm as they slowly gathered around the one thing she had never thought she would lose. The one thing she had not been prepared to lose.</p>

<p>“Her name was Whispering Dawn, and I loved her. I have been told my beauty is cold, like the frozen wastes of the north, but hers was warm, like sunshine and honey, and she brought me joy. We had met briefly in Dark's Reach, but at the time I saw her only as Jubilant SKy's sister. We then met a few years after I became an inspector, and we loved each other. Then she was taken.</p>

<p>“I well knew the signs by then, I saw the signature he left behind — the crushed petals mixed with blood —, but I still hoped against hope. The victims that were found were all found discarded, like garbage, within four weeks of their disappearance. They had been left to be found, and all had been dead for at least three days. There was suggestions that he'd either had victims concurrently, or at least catching a new victim right after having killed his prior one. So, I still had hope.</p>

<p>“She had been gone for three weeks. I was getting closer. I know I was, because when I was on my way home right before dawn one snowy day, I suddenly stepped on a red rose, the red petals crushing beneath my boot. The sun was rising, the blood red tones mixing with my blood as someone came up behind me and beat me over the head.”</p>

<p>She stopped, watching her own reflection in the glass of amber liquid, lost in her own thoughts.</p>

<p>“When I woke up again, I was bound and blindfolded. A man was there as well, his voice slightly guttural, deep and hushed. As he spoke he sent shivers down my spine. He taunted me, asking if I really thought I could have challenged him. If I had any idea who he was.”</p>

<p>Once again she paused, forcing herself to not get lost in things not to speak of, her hand going to her collar bone.</p>

<p>“He left me right before darkness fell, and I could hear the howling of hungry ghosts. Even worse, I could hear sobbing, and I knew then that Whispering Dawn was dead. That he had killed her, right before he took me. I also knew that if I did not get ourselves free, there was a risk that she would tear me apart once her higher soul had departed. And even if she didn't, I had no way of knowing how many victims he was holding prisoner here, or where the others were.</p>

<p>“It was the third night that they tore into the room I was bound in. I heard them howling, and Whispering Dawn was with them. She was part pleaading for help, part looking for revenge, not caring who or what she took out her revenge on. I knew it was a fool's errand, but I could not — would not — die without even attempting to save them.</p>

<p>“I pleaded with them, with her, telling them that I was a victim too, that it would not serve them well to take out their anger and hate on me.”</p>

<p>She exhaled, taking a sip of her drink.</p>

<p>“It was pure luck that the first bite managed to instead break the ropes, allowing me to pull off my blindfold to see these poor abused creatures as they were, as they'd been turned into. I backed into a corner, all while begging them to remember what they had been, and it seemed like I could almost reach Whispering Dawn, but then the second ghost lunged into me, tearing into my arm. I knew I was going to die, and I did the only thing I could think of. I prayed to the world at large, that it would help them, show them the mercy they hadn't gotten, to give them peace.”</p>

<h3 id="exaltation">Exaltation</h3>

<p>It was hard for her to continue explaning, and it felt too private to share the intimate details, so she only said: “I exalted”, as her mind remembered the details of how powerful she felt. She saw a world of injustice, of pain and suffering, the pour souls living — and unliving — through it. She felt the need to fix it, to help the ones who could not speak up for themselves, and as she knew that she would bring it to pass, she knew her true fate, the room ablaze with the light of the noon sun, the ghosts pulling back, giving her enough breathing space to free herself of the bonds.</p>

<p>She grieved the need for those actions, but she struck them down, burning their corpses with a touch a touch. She wept, because knew that even with those actions, it was too late for most of them. If they had not answered the call of Lethe, they were trapped until their master — her master — had accepted Lethe. She looked into the dead eyes of Whispering Dawn, a moment of peace from her ghost, and then she burned her in a blaze of heavenly fire, giving her up to save her, weeping until she could weep no more.</p>

<p>She found an old cloak to wrap up in, fleeing as she tried to find her way back, to get backup. After all, even though she was still feeling the power coursing through her veins, she was well aware that she was a young exalt. If their captor was more than just hot air, he might be able to defeat her, and that would help no one.</p>

<p>When she returned with a few squads, the cottage she had been held prisoner in was empty. He had most likely arrived at dawn and found her missing, and decided not to wait for her return. There was precious little she could salvage, but she did find a few keepsakes from his prior victims that she brought with her, to never forget. Of course, she would also never be able to forget the glyph burned into the skin on her collar bone, the telltale of the destiny her ghost was foretold to have.</p>

<p>The guard of Icehome would not have objected to her staying in the guard, though some of them were a bit wary. She however felt that it was more important that she understand what she was, how she had come to be that, and why. Also, it seemed quite clear to her that he had moved on. She had to find him.</p>

<h3 id="aftermath">Fate and Destiny</h3>

<p>She partly wandered, partly investigated, the path taking her further south. Occasionally she heard things that suggested her quarry had gone this way or that, but more than anything she followed memories, thoughts dreams of a past.</p>

<p>That past eventually led her up a mountain on one of the small islands in the frozen North Sea, into a sturdy marble building seeming a part of the snow and ice, though it was warm and welcoming inside.</p>

<p>She could feel the humming of power as she explored the rooms, each of them warmed by a never-dying fire, lit with beautifully carved lights. The library was decorated in mahogany with huge bookcases housing books from far more than a millennia ago. On the small reading table lay a few books, one with a bookmark in it. She felt the warmth of the charm at one end of the tassel, realising to her surprise that it was orichalcum decorated with opal. As she held it, she suddenly got a flash of memory.<aside></p>

<p>She saw the manse for the first time, crafted by her No Moon mate as a birthday present. She felt joy at it and the artifacts her mate had created, though it as always came with a bit of a sting at remembering what she had lost. Her Full Moon mate, dead against raksha so many years ago, and then replaced with a young one whom she could not love. Her mate deserved better, she knew, and she smiled and thanked for the gifts, her children in various stages of creation around her.</p>

<p>It was not just a fake thank-you either. Had she not still mourned and loved the man who had been with her for millennia, no one could have wanted a more attentive and loving mate. After all, not only had her mate found books from all over Creation to fill the manse with, there was the beautiful orichalcum circlet to hold the stone in, and the orichalcum switchklaive that could also act as a bookmark. She ran her fingers over the inscription, and smiled wistfully.</aside></p>

<p>She found the circlet in the basement, alongside a casket beautifully created in bronze with decorations of silver and gold, and though she had no memory of it, there was a tingling sensation that made her realise that this was her. Her prior incarnation, Lady Kerhia, Queen of the Winged Ones, lay there. A part of her recognized the craftmanship, and it became even more obvious when she compared the circlet and switchklaive that it had been crafted by the same hand: The No Moon that had loved her through the years.</p>

<p>A single feather of an eagle, cast in silver, paired with her own knowledge of the past suddenly filled her with dread and guilt. Her children! Marama's Fell, Camp 17, were they there? Had they been brutally murdered alongside other inmates as well? They had done nothing wrong, they had been good. She could not let them suffer there anymore. She had to help them. She had to get there, and find them.</p>

<p>And thus, suspicions of her dark fate hiding in Marama's Fell, alongside the fear that her past's beloved creations were still there, led her steps to Whitewall. She could not let them hurt longer, and she had to save the poor souls bound to Him.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-05-20 18:28:50]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-05-20 18:28:50]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[last-wish]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Articles</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/articles/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 16:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=21</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>21</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-06-01 16:08:20]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-01 16:08:20]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[articles]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Contact</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/contact/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 16:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=801</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[[contact-form-7 id="800" title="Contact"]]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>801</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-06-02 16:49:16]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-02 16:49:16]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[contact]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colophon</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/colophon/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 14:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=807</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The theme for MarieHogebrandt.se is © 2013 Marie Hogebrandt under the <a href="/LICENCE.txt">MIT Licence</a>, derived from <a href="http://www.rootstheme.com">Roots</a>, <a href="http://www.underscores.me">_s</a> and the <a href="http://www.goldengridsystem.com">Golden Grid System</a>, proudly powered by <a href="http://www.wordpress.org">WordPress</a>.</p>

<h2>Libraries</h2>

<dl>
<dt><a href="http://necolas.github.io/normalize.css/">Normalize</a></dt>
<dd>A CSS library to normalize the styles to compensate for different browsers</dd>

<dt><a href="http://typeplate.com/">Typeplate</a></dt>
<dd>Typography is not an accident, good typography even less so</dd>

<dt><a href="http://jquery.com/">jQuery</a></dt>
<dd><em>The</em> Javascript library for modern design</dd>

<dt><a href="http://modernizr.com/">Modernizr</a></dt>
<dd>Javascript library for checking capabilities</dd>

<dt><a href="http://selectivizr.com">Selectivizr</a></dt>
<dd>Polyfill for advanced CSS-selectors</dd>

<dt><a href="http://fancyapps.com/fancybox/">Fancybox</a></dt>
<dd>A lightbox script for mixed content</dd>

<dt><a href="https://github.com/brandonaaron/jquery-mousewheel">jQuery Mousewheel Plugin</a></dt>
<dd>Plugin to add cross-browser support for the mousewheel</dd>
</dl>

<h2>Icons <span class="amp">&amp;</span> Ornaments</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.weloveiconfonts.com">We love Icon Fonts!</a> — A free <span class="amp">&amp;</span> open source icon fonts hosting service for icons.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://entypo.com/">Entypo</a> by <a href="http://danielbruce.se/">Daniel Bruce</a></li>
<li><a href="http://fontello.github.io/brandico.font/demo.html">Brandico</a> by <a href="http://fontello.com/">Fontello</a></li>
<li><a href="http://fortawesome.github.io/Font-Awesome/">Font Awesome</a> by <a href="http://davegandy.com/">Dave Gandy</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.fontsquirrel.com/fonts/Printers-Ornaments-One">Printers Ornaments One</a> by Michelle Dixon</li>
<li>Logo is <a href="http://www.dafont.com/constanze-initials.font">Constanze Initials</a> by ClaudeP</li>
</ul>

<h2>Typography</h2>

<p>Both text and heading type are <a href="http://www.calendasplus.com">Calendas Plus</a> by <a href="http://www.atipo.es/">Atipo</a>, a beautiful fontface with a very classical air to it. I like the lines and variance in strokes, which creates a very pleasant view.</p>

<p>The various ornaments on headers and paragraphs, as well as the different styles of headers (crossheads for first three levels, indented sideheads for the following two and finally the run-in sidehead for the sixth level) are inspired by the masterwork <cite>The Elements of Typographic Style</cite> by Robert Bringhurst.</p>

<p>For some extra styling of typographical elements (such as wrapping ampersands in a <code>span</code> with the class <code>amp</code>) I use an updated version of <a href="https://github.com/Melindrea/wp-typography">WP-Typography</a>, originally created by <a href="http://kingdesk.com/">Jeffrey D. King</a>.</p>

<h2>Other design concerns</h2>

<dl>
<dt><a href="http://subtlepatterns.com/exclusive-paper/">Exclusive Paper</a> from Subtle Patterns</dt>
<dd>Background for the site, and overall Subtle Patterns is a nice site</dd>
</dl>

<h2>Development</h2>

<p>The creation of this theme is an experiment. It has been based on testing some of the newest and most interesting tools out there, as well as using tried-and-true methods.</p>

<h2>Language Abstraction</h2>

<dl>
<dt><a href="http://thesassway.com/">Sassy CSS</a></dt>
<dd>A Pre-processor language heavily based on CSS-syntax. Used together with <a href="http://compass-style.org">Compass</a> to bring even more ease into the creation of good CSS.</dd>

<dt><a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a></dt>
<dd>Though the HTML is written normally, posts <span class="amp">&amp;</span> pages are written using Markdown, within the context of WordPress the plugin <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/wp-markdown/">WP Markdown</a> by <a href="http://www.stephenharris.info/">Stephen Harris</a>.</dd>
</dl>

<h2>Development Tools</h2>

<h3>Dependencies Handler <span class="amp">&amp;</span> Package Managers</h3>

<dl>
<dt><a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a></dt>
<dd>A language in itself, but for my purposes uses a <code>gemfile</code> to install required gems, mainly CSSCSS and Sass.</dd>

<dt><a href="http://nodejs.org/">NodeJS</a></dt>
<dd>Server-side JavaScript, here only used for installation of build tools such as Grunt, using the package manager <code>npm</code> and <code>package.json</code> to install required packages</dd>

<dt><a href="http://bower.io/">Bower</a></dt>
<dd>Handling web dependencies such as Typeplate and WordPress, uses the file <code>bower.json</code></dd>

<dt><a href="http://getcomposer.org/">Composer</a></dt>
<dd>Dependency manager for PHP</dd>
</dl>

<h3>Various Tools</h3>

<dl>
<dt><a href="http://gruntjs.com/">GruntJS</a></dt>
<dd>According to it's creator, Grunt is <q>The JavaScript Task Runner</q>, used to automate boring chores such as automatically lint JavaScript and PHP, compile SCSS and build a lean, mean Modernizr machine. The specifications are found in the project's <a href="https://github.com/Melindrea/mariehogebrandt-se/blob/master/Gruntfile.js">Gruntfile</a></dd>

<dt><a href="http://yeoman.io/">Yeoman</a></dt>
<dd>A workflow more than anything else, where Yo is a scaffolder, pulling in files and creating default settings. This theme is based on the default webapp, but one of my WIP is to create a scaffolder for themes</dd>

<dt><a href="http://zmoazeni.github.io/csscss/">CSSCSS</a></dt>
<dd>A ruby gem (with a grunt wrapper) for checking CSS for duplicate styles, as one part of a better (and cleaner) codebase</dd>

<dt><a href="http://colorschemedesigner.com/">Color Scheme Designer</a></dt>
<dd>A good tool for prototyping colours that go well together</dd>
</dl>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>807</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-06-03 14:44:07]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-03 14:44:07]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[colophon]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Role Playing Characters</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/characters/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 15:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=809</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I play a lot of role playing games, mainly Exalted, Mutants and Masterminds, and Shadowrun.</p>

<p>If you are a fan of Exalted I strongly recommend <a href="http://www.unboundanima.com">Unbound Anima</a> which is a game set in the North, centered around Whitewall.</p>

<h2>List of Characters</h2>

<dl>
<dt><a href="/characters/last-wish">Last Wish</a>, Zenith on <a href="http://www.unboundanima.com">Unbound Anima</a></dt>
<dd>In the odd genre of "Noir Exalted" comes this detective with a tragic past and a nemesis who may strike again at any time</dd>

<dt><a href="/characters/shimmer-iced-mirage">Shimmer-Iced Mirage</a>, Full Moon on <a href="http://www.unboundanima.com">Unbound Anima</a></dt>
<dd>Her age unknown to everyone -- including herself --, her exotic beauty belies her caste</dd>
</dl>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>809</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-06-03 15:15:40]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-03 15:15:40]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[characters]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Shimmer-Iced Mirage</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/shimmer-iced-mirage/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 15:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=821</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"Once upon a time there lived the beautiful princess Medora, in a kingdom far, far away. Her mother had died when she was born, and her father, the good king Eldric, raised her. When she was sixteen, the sorcerer Talisker came to their lands, and he took the princess to his keep, to make her his eternal bride, his beautiful swan maiden. The young princess would easily have succumbed to his evil charms eventually, had not King Eldric announced throughout the lands that the one who could rescue the fair princess from the evil sorcerer would be given her hand in marriage, and half the kingdom.</p>

<p>The valiant prince Targenor heard the king's announcement, and he stormed to the keep of the evil sorcerer, fighting against all the monsters that protected it, to the central chamber where the beautiful princess was kept a prisoner, but there he met his match, the sorcerer who was as skilled in swordplay as he was magic. The valiant prince Targenor died of his wounds, and the sorcerer laughed, telling Medora that she would succumb to him, or she would perish.</p>

<p>She refused him, again and again, but no mortal woman could resist the charms of the sorcerer Talisker, and finally she begged him to take her and make her his."</p>

<p>Or, well. That is how the Luminary Raksha Talisker planned things. None of the involved know how long it took, but he found mortals to make into his puppets to play out the fairy tale, finding a beautiful girl, who's name is no longer one that is remembered, for the role of Medora.</p>

<p>Up until the valiant prince Targenor came to the keep of the evil sorcerer everything went as it was supposed to. Medora was very beautiful, and Talisker congratulated himself, watching his bound bride hanging on the wall. The prince, too, fought valiantly, but of course in vain. How could even a godblood compete with a raksha? He, then, approached Medora, giving her the choice of becoming his, or perish. The fair, gentle maiden chose to turn herself into a beautiful swan rather than succumb to his advances, forever to grieve the loss... no, wait. That's not <em>quite</em> how it happened.</p>

<p>"Medora" doesn't remember her own name. She has vague memories of having learned how to fight, and of a bearded person who she believes is her father, but mortals do have little to set against one of the cruel fair folk. For her, the revolution started earlier than Talisker realised. It started seeing the children that were abused and used as a mix of pets and walking food sources. It started seeing the servants who no longer had semblance of rational thought. It started seeing the guild merchants selling more slaves to be used in Talisker's story. And it finished seeing the attractive Targenor struck down for nothing more than the amusement of the raksha.</p>

<p>Talisker approached her, and he told her that either she would become his, or she would perish. She snarled and tore the chains off the wall, as if it had been nothing more than spiderweb, using the fair folk's story against him as she grew into the shape of a beastman swan, striking him hard, using the chains she'd torn out of the wall to beat him and his entourage up. The poor hobgoblins were no match to the furious full moon, and even the Luminary had to flee. He threw his cloak around himself, stunting his escape, leaving her with the words: "I will return, my love, once you have calmed down. I am sure we can work things out!"</p>

<p>Grumbling over the raksha, Medora then moved to check on Targenor, who was alive, but unconscious. She was still bound by the chains, and trying to tear them apart didn't do much, so she had no other choice than to lift up Targenor into her arms and carrying him out, bringing the various children and servants who were still alive enough to be saved out of the keep. Those who were not she gave what help she could. Her "father" was overjoyed to see his daughter safe and sound, and it was a rag-tag band of 20 who followed the newly exalted Lunar out of the freehold, the few raksha left fleeing from the fury of the enraged Swan Maiden.</p>

<p>As night fell, they camped underneath the full moon. Medora had managed to slip out of her bonds by shifting into a swan, but she could feel pieces of herself getting lost with every shift. She could not sleep at all, the moon calling her out. She let her gaze flicker over the area, when her gaze fell on a huntress whose features glittered in silver. As the eyes of the Swan Maiden and the Bloody Huntress met, the goddess raised her bow in greeting towards her newest child, before she turned into a silver beam.</p>

<p>They continued through the wyld. After they had gotten into the bordermarches, they saw a heart-wrenching sight. It was a caravan of guilders, travelling through the wyld, most likely heading for the freehold they'd just left, or possibly another freehold. They saw the slaves, and then the Swan Maiden saw red. The former slaves weren't fighters, and the caravan's guards were powerful. She would've lost all of them, had not a group of four Lunars joined into the fray, helping her and the freed slaves to fight back. As the Swan Maiden met the eye of the merchant, she suddenly went cold. A flashback to him and her. She saw what he'd done to her before turning her over to the Raksha, and she lunged. When she saw clearly again, he was bludgeoned to death, the slight repaid in blood. As it may be, it as likely that the victim of her attack was a brother, son, grandson or related even farther away, as the Swan Maiden may have been a prisoner for as few as a two or three years, or as much as up to hundred, maybe even more.</p>

<p>Targenor was one of the few who hadn't been brainwashed into joining the story, but was a god-blood, an offshoot of... Well, neither he nor his mother ever knew. He had been foolish enough to want to play the hero when he heard about the threats of the sorcerer against the peaceful kingdom, and hadn't realised how much in over his head he was until he came to the kingdom and realised how staged it was. At that time, however, he felt that he had to do something. He couldn't just sit back and let the Raksha do its' thing, so he continued to play the role that had been suggested to him, hoping against the odds he could find a way to save them. At first, he'd been slightly bitter that he had been such a complete failure that the princess had to save <em>him</em>, but in the end he came around, and they both enjoyed each other's company as they travelled.</p>

<p>The pack that had been sent to retrieve her consisted of two full moons, a no moon, and a teasing changing moon, all of which she got along fairly well with. The last bit of the way, she had to leave the slaves and Targenor, but promised she would return to them. He, in turn, promised that he'd look after them. Eldric wasn't her father, they both knew that, but they still felt like family, so she hugged him closely before leaving, promising him, too, that she would return. They were all the family most of them had, after all.</p>

<p>The no moon, Wind Beneath Wings, was a crane totem, not that much of an elder, but old enough. He gave the Swan Maiden an appreciative look as she came in with the pack, and of course she was still stunning. Through the trip from the freehold, she had not had a chance to replace her outfit, and gossamer was very sturdy, leaving her in the incredibly beautiful white gown that Talisker had put her in, matched with a cloak. Say what you want about Raksha, but they know how to make things last. Wind Beneath Wings glanced over at the full moon who'd led the pack, thanking them for having gotten her to him safely, noting that the pact appeared to have gotten a new changing moon. This would have gone over quite smoothly, had not the changing moon of the rescue pack decided to be a tease, leaning in to murmur to the Swan Maiden that the no moon had suggested that she couldn't fight. That she was just a pretty face. And then the changing moon sat back to watch the ensuing chaos. After all, it had been quite funny (per his packmates) watching her go after him for the same mistake.</p>

<p>The Swan Maiden, of course, was no match to the No Moon. Full Moon or not, she did not have the experience needed to beat him up, though he noted that she had a very good arm on her. He knocked her out, and when she woke up they talked instead, and came to an agreement. He agreed that he'd been a bit premature with setting her caste and would go into the trials with an open mind, she agreed that attacking another member of the pact, especially the elder trying to keep you out of becoming a chimera, was not wise.</p>

<p>The rest of the trials were fairly standard. One of them was to pick animals to fulfill certain roles, and as she was in the north she picked a wolf to hunt with, a raven to sneak with and also to be able to pass through cities unseen, and a hare for when she needed to travel in high speeds along the ground. With her massive Beast-form she could fight, and with her Spirit Shape she could fly. Another was to find a particular Raksha and take from him the sword he carried, which she did by luring him into a false sense of safety with her grace and beauty, before she attacked. A third was strange to her: to retrieve an urn of a pool of silver in the wyld. Moonsilver, she was told, once she came back.</p>

<p>Every night he would talk to her while working on the painful tattoos, finding out more about her, incorporating who she was - or what she remembered - into her tattoos. Finally he finished them but for two things: What name she should use as her deed-name, and what would she be the steward of? She chose the name of Shimmer-Iced Mirage, evoking the silver tattoos and the view of Luna, almost unreal, and the stewardship was obvious: The Wyld.</p>

<p>Then came a time of tutelage. She travelled with the pack that had rescued her, coming to know them very well. The leader was a bull totem called Steady Charge, his next-in-command was the raiton no moon Sails on Obsidian Skies. The omega of the pack, if such a thing, was the coyote changing moon Teasing Laughter, and the final member of the pack was the eagle Brilliant Flight. They were all of the Swords of Luna, which seemed fitting. Teasing Laughter and Grace became on-again, off-again lovers, and always rivals. At the end of her tutelage, having been with them little over a year, Wind Beneath Wings sent a message for them. He explained that it was now time she went out on her own. As a parting present he gave her a beautiful moonsilver chain daiklaive, which told the story of a Swan Princess who freed herself from the shackles of the fair folk, who fought her way into possession of the Sword of an Anarch, the shackles and Sword having been both used to create it. She smiled, a beautiful smile on beautiful features, and when asked what she would name it, the answer was simple. "This is my fairy tale."</p>

<p>The small village had blossomed, once she returned to it. Some of the people had made new lives for themselves, starting to trade with their neighbours, but a few were restless. She stayed for three months, and they crowned her ruler of their village. When she left, it was with Targenor by her side, as well as twenty of the more adventurous former slaves. Eldric stayed back, ruling in her stead, all of them having sworn loyalty to Medora, their Swan Maiden, Graceful Retribution...</p>

<p>Together they travelled through the countryside, scavenging what they could, hankering on. Mirage would hunt and they'd sell the pelts, and sometimes they were guards to caravans, but never the guild, and never slave caravans. One day she was out swimming in a river when she felt the pull of essence. She swum down, finding a manse at the bottom of the river, a small pagoda among the seaweed, filled with raging water swirling. It was not easy to attune to it, but she pulled it off in the end, being just slightly singed. The hearthstone she set in her Chain Daiklaive, before moving on.</p>

<p>They settled in two areas: Inside Whitewall to have a safe haven, if necessary, and a small camp closer to the mountains, so that they would be ready, should the fair ones threaten the city or villages nearby.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>821</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-06-03 15:29:30]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-03 15:29:30]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[shimmer-iced-mirage]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Marie</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 13:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=2</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I live in Sweden and work at <a href="http://www.pineberry.com" rel="external">Pineberry</a> in Stockholm as a developer (mainly PHP/WordPress, some Python) since 2012.</p>

<p>In my spare time I explore the new and cool things that pop up every so often, discard some fairly soon, though others stick with me. I am a bit of an inspiration butterfly, and jump from project to project aimlessly. I will write for a month or two, then do digital art for a month or two, pick up the redesign of my page for the umpteenth time, etc. Unfortunately these butterfly tendencies are paired with a certain amount of perfectionism, which is one of the reasons I lose interest: If I can't get something as awesome as I want it to be, I just stop.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>855</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-04-06 13:05:47]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-04-06 13:05:47]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[home]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Developer, Role player, Idealist]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes_0_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Clean code]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes_0_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes_1_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Innovative solutions]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes_1_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes_2_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Humanist serif fonts]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes_2_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes_3_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Bad puns]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes_3_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes_4_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Automation]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes_4_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes_5_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Markdown for posts/pages]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes_5_like]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[likes]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[6]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_likes]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_13]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes_0_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Repetive tasks]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes_0_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_16]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes_1_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Hacks]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes_1_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_16]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes_2_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Realist sans-serif fonts]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes_2_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_16]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes_3_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Inline CSS and JavaScript (by hand <em>or</em> JavaScript)]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes_3_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_16]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes_4_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Hard-to-reproduce bugs]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes_4_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_16]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes_5_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[What-you-see-is-kind-of-sort-of-what-you-get-in-the-worst-way-possible]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes_5_dislike]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_16]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[dislikes]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[6]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_dislikes]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_15]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[960]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_yoast_wpseo_title]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Marie Hogebrandt]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Gallery</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/gallery/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 20:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.local/?page_id=835</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest pieces of art from my DeviantArt page.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>875</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-06-06 20:54:15]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-06 20:54:15]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[gallery]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[melindrea82]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Testing Typography</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=973</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=973</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>This is the second header</h2>

<p>Some text, text, text.</p>

<h3>Third header</h3>

<p>More text.</p>

<h4>Fourth header</h4>

<p>Yet more text.</p>

<h5>Fifth header</h5>

<p>Text.</p>

<h6>Sixth header</h6>

<p>Yeesh, that's a lot of headers and text...</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>973</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-07-02 15:41:04]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[0000-00-00 00:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[testing-typography]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Ice-Barbarians</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/ice-barbarians/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 19:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1079</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was a cold midwinter night. The full moon shone high on the sky, and Caroline stared out over the moors. She heard the bells on the cows, and calls from shepherds gathering their flocks. She remembered the warning clearly: This was a dangerous night. No animals must be outside. If they where, they would become lost. The key in the door turned, and the old woman stepped in with a tray. Caroline gave her a gracious glance, but did not approach the table until the door was closed and locked again.</p>

<p>Then she stepped up and moved towards the table. The dark silk of the dress rustled, and the chain around her ankle clinked with each step. She knew that the servants gossiped, but she was above that. She, daughter of queens, of kings, would never allow the gossip to reach her.</p>

<p>Once she had eaten her fill she pulled the cord to the bell, which chimed cheerfully despite her dark moods. Carefully she walked back to the window, reaching for the embroidery on the table. The old woman came to bring the tray back to the kitchen, but Caroline refused to give her even a glance. She stared out through the window and let her fingers work with the embroidery. She felt every stitch, every seam, and under her fingers an epic story grew.</p>

<p>The storm howled outside, and nothing living was on the moor. Her window was covered with snowflakes, and with care she opened it to clear it from at least the worst of the snow. She heard class breaking in another part of the castle, and startled she turned away from the window.</p>

<p>Suddenly both her windows where torn open, and she could feel the cold biting her into the bone. She turned around to close it, but froze when she saw him.</p>

<p>A man, dressed in furs, stood in the window. He gave her a long look before he grabbed her wrist and pulled her to him. She fought him as much as she could, but with another tug she was on the white horse. He grunted as he saw the chain around her ankle, pulling her skirt up in the most indecent manners before he tore the chain off as if it was thread.</p>

<p>She screamed, but his hand over her mouth silenced her, and she shivered from the cold. Her beautiful gown of silk and lace was not suited for the chill of a midwinter night. He opened his heavy fur cloak and pulled her into it so that she sat with her back pressed against his. She shivered and shook from chill and worry, but could do nothing but hold on as the wild hunt continued over the landscape. She felt his rough hand around her slender waist and closed her eyes. His body was warm against hers, and all old stories came to her memory.</p>

<p>The ice-barbarians, the wild hunt that stole both people and animals if they could. It was said that they cannibals, and she knew that it was worse than death to be in their hands. She shivered again and opened her eyes to figure out where they were. As she looked down she saw that they’d left her kingdom behind. There was no rescue now. At least not from anyone else. Of course, before she could figure out how to get out of this they would have to land.</p>

<p>She felt his hand playing over her bodice and suppressed a shiver. She tried to pull away, but he pressed her against her closer. For now there was nothing she could do to escape his unwelcome advances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1079</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2013-12-22 21:03:55]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-12-22 19:03:55]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[ice-barbarians]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Writer&#039;s Block</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 19:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1084</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I write and read, and this section is the combination of those hobbies.</p>

<h2>Writerly tidbits</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="/writers-block/wip-blog-tour">WIP Blog Tour</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Short stories/ideas</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="/writers-block/last-wish">Last Wish</a>, Exalted Fan-fic</li>
<li><a href="/writers-block/shimmer-iced-mirage">Shimmer-Iced Mirage</a>, Exalted Fan-fic</li>
<li><a href="/writers-block/ice-barbarians">Ice-Barbarians</a>, concept fiction for an Epic fantasy</li>
<li><a href="/writers-block/hat-shuffle-story">The Attic</a>, short story/intro fiction</li>
</ul>

<h2>Featured content</h2>

<ul class="thumbnails gallery" id="gallery-1">
  <li>
    <a href="/assets/media/Print-HW1-Cover.jpg" class="thumbnail"><img alt="Harlow Whittaker & the Soothsayers Cover" src="/assets/media/Print-HW1-Cover-200x200.jpg" class="img-rounded" /></a> <p class="wp-caption-text">
      <a href="/writers-block/harlow-whittaker-soothsayers/"><strong>Review</strong>: 4 Stars</a>
    </p>
  </li>
  
  <li>
    <a href="/assets/media/antipathia-cover.jpg" class="thumbnail"><img alt="Antipathia Cover" src="/assets/media/antipathia-cover-200x200.jpg" class="img-rounded" /></a> <p class="wp-caption-text">
      <a href="/writers-block/antipathia/"><strong>Review</strong>: 5 Stars</a>
    </p>
  </li>
  
  <li>
    <a href="/assets/media/cover.jpg" class="thumbnail"><img alt="Dying for a Living Cover" src="/assets/media/cover-200x200.jpg" class="img-rounded" /></a> <p class="wp-caption-text">
      <a href="/writers-block/dying-living/"><strong>Review</strong>: 3 Stars</a>
    </p>
  </li>
  
  <li>
    <a href="/assets/media/SLcover-72p-9x6.jpg" class="thumbnail"><img alt="Shadowed Lights Cover" src="/assets/media/SLcover-72p-9x6-200x200.jpg" class="img-rounded" /></a> <p class="wp-caption-text">
      <a href="/writers-block/shadowed-lights/"><strong>Promo</strong></a>
    </p>
  </li>
  
  <li>
    <a href="/assets/media/We-Wont-Feel-a-Thing-FINAL-COVER.jpg" class="thumbnail"><img alt="We won't feel a thing cover" src="/assets/media/We-Wont-Feel-a-Thing-FINAL-COVER-200x200.jpg" class="img-rounded" /></a> <p class="wp-caption-text">
      <a href="/writers-block/wont-feel-thing-j-c-lillis/"><strong>Promo</strong></a>
    </p>
  </li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1084</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-02-09 21:24:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-02-09 19:24:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[writers-block]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>We Won&#039;t Feel a Thing</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/wont-feel-thing-j-c-lillis/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 20:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1088</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/media/We-Wont-Feel-a-Thing-FINAL-COVER-640x1024.jpg" alt="We Won&#039;t Feel a Thing Cover" width="640" height="1024" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1090" /></p>

<p>I have the honour to be one of the people revealing the cover of new-and-upcoming "We Won't Feel a Thing", a YA contemporary romantic fantasy, by <a href="http://www.jclillis.com">J.C. Lillis</a>. It will be in stores March 31, 2014.</p>

<h2>J.C. Lillis says</h2>

<h3>Book blurb</h3>

<p>Seventeen-year-old best friends Rachel and Riley are in forbidden love. Their situation’s ... complicated. And their timing couldn’t be worse---in just one month, he leaves for California and she starts college in New York. The absolute last thing they need is a reckless secret-love confession mucking up their perfect plans. There’s only one logical option: scientific intervention. Desperate for a quick fix, they sign up for WAVES, an experimental self-help program led by mysterious scientist David A. Kerning. He swears his Forbidden Love Module can turn passion back to safe platonic friendship in “six easy steps.” But when you arm yourself with an untested program, side effects are unpredictable. And sometimes when you fight love—love fights back.</p>

<h3>About the book cover</h3>

<p>I had this cover idea in my head pretty early on—the waves are a recurring image, and there’s also a Significant Umbrella in the story. I worked closely with my awesome cover designer, Mindy Dunn, who took the basic idea and made it beauteous. The book is whimsical and romantic (and hopefully funny), and I think the cover captures the tone really well. I hope you like it!</p>

<h3>About the Author</h3>

<p>J.C. Lillis lives in Baltimore with her patient family and a ragtag band of tropical fish, some of which will be dead by the time you read this. WE WON’T FEEL A THING is her second YA novel; she also wrote HOW TO REPAIR A MECHANICAL HEART, because she wanted to read a book about two sci-fi fanboys in love and there wasn’t one handy. She loves koi ponds, abandoned amusement parks, and peanut butter &amp; banana sandwiches. She hates paper cuts, cabbage, and writing bios.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1088</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-02-09 22:12:07]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-02-09 20:12:07]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[wont-feel-thing-j-c-lillis]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1090]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[ by J.C. Lillis]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Creation of a fancy steampunk outfit</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/fancy-steampunk-outfit/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 18:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1096</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mariehogebrandt.se/assets/media/kjol-164x300.png" alt="Two-layered skirt with peasant-blouse" width="164" height="300" class="alignleft img-polaroid size-medium wp-image-1099" /> In 2011 I made an outfit for a fancy occasion (a wedding). With some assistance from my partner I decided on a look with a layered skirt and a beautiful peasant blouse in a silver-purple fabric. Though I was pleased with it immediately, I soon realised how clumsy it looked. It did nothing to enhance my curves.</p>

<p><img src="http://mariehogebrandt.se/assets/media/corset-174x300.jpg" alt="Corset in black and silver" width="174" height="300" class="alignright img-polaroid size-medium wp-image-1098" /> ... which leads into my present for myself Christmas 2012: A beautiful corset from <a href="http://violalagher.se">Viola Lagher</a>. I had bought a corset from them prior (while they were known as Snöfrid Holgersdotter), a beautiful Revenge de la Femme, but it had gotten too worn. Though I could have picked up one of their normal patterns, what I decided on was a mix between two corsets: An overbust with a sweetheart cut, and an underbust that ended lower on the hip, to create a smoother curve. I decided on black with visible silver piping, to give it a classic and timeless look that would go well with everything, while being more exciting than just a simple black corset.</p>

<h2>Transformation</h2>

<p>My intention is to take my long skirt and create a silhouette that's closer to the S-curve of the 1890s. I have found an old ball gown that I will take the black underskirt from to give some extra volume, where most of it will be drawn back with a fairly straight-hanging front. Ribbons in brown and golds, as well as black lace, will be attached to the hem of both the navy blue skirt and the shimmering top-layer.</p>

<p>To match this I intend to buy a shirt in the style of the 1800s, with a classic cravat, to mix the feminine with the masculine. Maybe even a pair of goggles. Most certainly a few cogwheels or similar.</p>

<h2>Update: Summer 2014</h2>

<p>The skirt is underway! The waist band (the same brocade-like fabric as the outer skirt) is reinforced (with denim, amusingly). Each seam is covered with a beautiful band of brown and gold, hand-sewn onto it. <img src="http://mariehogebrandt.se//assets/media/linning-300x200.jpg" alt="Skirt waist band" width="300" height="200" class="alignright img-polaroid size-medium  wp-image-1198" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1096</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-02-12 20:49:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-02-12 18:49:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[fancy-steampunk-outfit]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Hat-shuffle story</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/hat-shuffle-story/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 15:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1106</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This story is part of a game on twitter, spear-headed by <a href="http://nanopals.blogspot.se/2014/02/the-hat-been-shuffled-yo.html">NaNoPals</a>. The idea is to write a story of 1K-5K using prompts of a <strong>character</strong>, a <strong>setting</strong> and an <strong>object</strong>. Mine were the following:</p>

<dl>
<dt>Character</dt>
<dd>Lesbian roller derby girl</dd>
<dt>Setting</dt>
<dd>An attic</dd>
<dt>Object</dt>
<dd>A low-quality statue/figurine</dd>
</dl>

<p>Without further ado, I present:</p>

<h2>The attic</h2>

<p>It was noon on a Saturday. Justine rang the doorbell with a dejected sigh. Her grandmother, a beatific woman with white hair in a thick braid, let her in.</p>

<p>"Sweety, it's so nice to see you!" She kissed Justine on both cheeks. Justine gave her a tense smile, changing the grip on her bookbag.</p>

<p>"Nana, you said you needed help?" She stepped into the large hall, the scents of old hitting her between the eyes. Her annoyance melted away.</p>

<p>"Yes, but first, would you like some tea?" The old smell was usurped by wafts from the kitchen: fresh scones. "I have homemade lemon curd, just as you like it."</p>

<p>A grumble coming from her stomach reminded Justine that it had been a while since she ate last, and she nodded. "Yes, please. Is this about grand-père?"</p>

<p>"What makes you think that it's about him?" Nana's eyes were wide and innocent, the cane tapping in the floor as she led the way into the sitting room. Justine sank down in one of the soft armchairs, resting her head back against the headrest. Her grandmother served the tea and pushed a tray of honey, fresh scones, butter and lemon curd towards Justine.</p>

<p>"Whenever there's something urgently you need help with, it seems to be connected to him." Though her tone as testy, she bit into a scone with evident pleasure before she took a sip of tea to wash it down. "And more often than not, something he found on one of his travels." Her gaze fell on items in the sitting room, one more absurd than the other. One in particular, a fertility statue reminiscent of Venus from Willendorf, caught her glance. Her cheeks flushed momentarily.</p>

<p>"Well, now that you mention it ..." Nana stirred a dollop of honey into her tea. "There was the small matter with a statue that seems to have gone missing."</p>

<p>"Gone missing?" Justine raise an eyebrow as she watched her Nana. "How did it go missing?"</p>

<p>"I'm really not sure," said Nana and sighed. "I was certain that it was on the mantlepiece, but this morning I didn't see it." She took a delicate bite of her scone. "So you'll help?"</p>

<p>"Can I do anything else?" Justine shook her head. "But let me see if I get this straight: You called me away from roller-skate practice because you've forgotten where you put one of grand-père's moldy old statues?"</p>

<p>"It is not moldy. He brought it back from Romania during his last travel. Maybe it's up in the attic again?"</p>

<p>"Why would it be up in the attic?" Justine pushed a hand through her dark, straight hair. "And what do you mean, again?"</p>

<p>"Oh, you know this place. Some of the things, they've forgotten that they're not where they were, so they wander. So many things end up in the attic. I almost wonder if Jean-Marie did something to it. It's a maze."</p>

<p>"It's just an attic, Nana!" Justine patted Nana's hand. "Alright, I'll go up and take a look, but I can't stay too long. Chris and I have a date later tonight."</p>

<p>"Oh, lovely! How is Christina? Well, I hope?"</p>

<p>"Yes, she's fine. A bit freaked about the apartment, but ..." She shruggged. "I think she's worried that I'm not serious, or that I'll change my mind."</p>

<p>"Silly girl. Of course you won't, sweety." Nana patted her cheek. "Well, if you're all done with your tea, maybe head up to the attic? The sooner you find the statue, the sooner you can go to meet Christina."</p>

<p>"Alright. What am I looking for, again? A statue, but how big? What does it look like?"</p>

<p>"Oh, it's an old thing. Clay, with some traces of paint. Some kind of shaman or witch, kneeling. I'm sure you'll know it when you see it."</p>

<p>Justine sighed inwardly, before nodding. Downing the last of the tea she walked towards the hall and up the stairs. She remembered the attic: grand-père loved to show her the things he kept from his travels. Lovely old Nana, getting battier every year, but as long as she could take care of herself with just some help, she could stay in the house. After all, it's where she had moved as a bride, where she'd had her children and where she'd become a widow.</p>

<p>"Though occasionally I wonder", said Justine as she slid the ladder down. "What really happened to grand-père?" She climbed up, looking around the dark, dry place. She sneezed as the dust tickled her nose. One time. Two times. "Sheesh, Nana," she muttered as she wiped her eyes and nose. "Would it kill you to have someone dust this place, if only occasionally?"</p>

<p>The light slowly flooded the area. Shadows danced in the sharpness of the lightbulbs gently twirling from their chains. The area was silent, waiting. A chill ran up her spine, and she surpressed a shudder. "Don't be ridiculus", she told herself sternly. "You've never been afraid of the dark before, so stop making things up."</p>

<p>Her voice echoed strangely as she moved between suitcases and shelfs. Each turn stranger than the other. Here was the collection of statues grand-père had brought with him home from Ethiopia, there the one from a dig in Scotland. When the clock downstairs struck she froze.</p>

<p>"Wait. Three pm? That can't be right." She glanced at her armwatch. The battery was dead---again---and it was still at 12.35. With a sigh she turned to go back downstairs. The lightbulbs high above her still twirled in their chains, but every step took her deeper into the attic. She no longer recognized anything. With every turn she saw new statues, new figurines, new knick-knacks. The smell of dust and mothballs was overpowering. Nana was right; it was a maze, and now she wanted nothing more than to escape it.</p>

<p>Footsteps echoed. The lights dimmed and she froze.</p>

<p>"He-- Hello?" Her voice quivered. There, a small figurine! She grasped it as a weapon.</p>

<p>There was no answer. She exhaled, her hands trembling. What was it Nana had said? "I had to call the police. He went up to the attic and never came back down." <em>Pull yourself together, Justine. You're just being silly now. You took a wrong turn, that's all!</em> "Is that so?" She asked herself, her voice hushed. "Then explain to me how I'm not finding my way back. It's not that big a house!" Her thoughts did not answer, no matter how much she wished that there was a logical explanation.</p>

<p>The dark, dry area was silent in anticipation. She could hear her own heart beat. Da-dum. Da-dum. The lights high above glittered and flickered. A shadow stepped out of the corner. The darkness parted to release the hood that shaded the face, the cloak that belied any human form beneath. Her lips parted as she stared, dread filling her eyes. Da-dum. Da-dum.</p>

<p>Then silence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1106</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-02-15 17:28:10]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-02-15 15:28:10]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hat-shuffle-story]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Shadowed Lights</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/shadowed-lights/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 16:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1115</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/media/SLcover-72p-9x6.jpg" alt="SLcover-72p-9x6" width="432" height="648" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1117" /> <em>Out in February 2014</em></p>

<p><em>This is a promo from the author</em></p>

<p>When her sister loses her house to Hurricane Sandy, Delaney Griffin welcomes the family into her home. Months later, with five noisy kids and an overbearing brother-in-law threatening her sanity, Delaney spends much of her free time at the wildlife refuge, which also works as her refuge. Still, the lack of privacy, along with space to dance, her only passionate release, causes her debilitating social anxiety to escalate.</p>

<p>Eli Forrester has come from small town Indiana to Barnegat, New Jersey with his company to help restore the coast. A high rise worker who loves new people and new places, he fears nothing, except water. When he accidentally kicks one of the sea critters Delaney is trying to help rescue, he is drawn to the quiet New Jersey girl. Unwilling to take her cues to leave her alone, Eli is alternately put off and turned on by her odd behavior.</p>

<p>Under shadow of devastation, fear, and forced separation, Delaney and Eli search for their own rescue light.</p>

<h2>About the author</h2>

<p>Ella M. Kaye is a pen name for author LK Hunsaker's shorter, spicier romance line featuring dancers of various genres in lighthouse settings. They focus on the darker side of life, with such themes as devastating injury, destruction, and emotional trauma. At the end, though, there is always a light. Kaye's forte is deep, fully drawn characterization. Find her at <a href="http://ellamkaye.com">ellamkaye.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1115</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-02-18 18:07:27]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-02-18 16:07:27]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[shadowed-lights]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[by Ella M. Kaye]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1117]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Wolf that ate the Sun-Child</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/wolf-ate-sun-child/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 22:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1125</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This was based on a freewriting wordsprint that had the first version of the first scene once it was finished. At that point, Vanlandi was male, and Lynessa was known as Caroline. <a href="/writers-block/ice-barbarians/">Read it here.</a></p>

<p>Main PoV is Lynessa. She is a princess from a "Medievalesque" kingdom. Probably 16-18, because she is in the age where she'll be forced to marry soon. Among her people, men are mages and not women, and marriage is between a man and a woman. If two men or two women are in love they can only be illicit lovers, but it's not less accepted than having an opposite-gender lover (in fact, for women it's more accepted, due to children).</p>

<p>Secondary PoV is Vanlandi. Vanlandi's father was a stubborn old coot who bragged himself into a corner when his second wife was pregnant with his first child. He'd bragged to everyone about his strong song, so when Vanlandi was born he refused to acknowledge her as his daughter, thus having her raised as a boy. This, not surprisingly, has led to a somewhat confused MC. Her culture is very much based on gender roles where the men are warriors and hunters, and the women deal with the home and ensuring that the base is settled. Magic is also the province of women. Oh, and they're also barbarians living in a magical glacier, with flying horses built like ardenners, who eat snow.</p>

<p>Vanlandi's people raid Lynessa's people regularly. The story starts with Lynessa being grabbed by Vanlandi, who brings her to the glacier. Lynessa's horror turns to confusion as she learns that Vanlandi sees this as an actual marriage. After all, in her culture, marriage is only between a man and a woman.</p>

<p>Obviously Vanlandi and Lynessa will fall for each other, with all their quirks, though it's going to take a while, since we have a lot of culture clashing. Both are from very rich cultures with a lot of details that's odd to the other (and to the readers).</p>

<p>Of course, there's more to this than a romance between a naive princess needing to find a backbone (and magic) and a badass barbarian chieftain who needs to prove that she's just as good a leader as her father. As hard as it is to live up to a great prior leader is without the extra complication, she is also going to eventually need to deal with being a woman.</p>

<p>The full story starts a few months after Lynessa comes to the glacier. The Rider that carries the Sun-Child across the sky ends up stumbling, so the Wolf chasing them devours the Sun-Child. The world will die without light, and Vanlandi knows that she has to do something. Her mother, the Seer, claims that the spirits demand that Lynessa joins her, so the two head out, travelling to the spirit world, then back, tracking the Wolf, up into the heavens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1125</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-02-21 00:14:04]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-02-20 22:14:04]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[wolf-ate-sun-child]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Dying for a Living</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/dying-living/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 16:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1136</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/media/cover-640x1024.jpg" alt="Dying for a living Cover" width="640" height="1024" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1133" /> <em>Disclaimer: I was given a copy of this book for review.</em></p>

<p><strong>Stars: 3</strong></p>

<h2>Review</h2>

<p><q>Dying for a living</q> is set in an undefined future where there are particular people who have the ability to come back from the dead. This triggered a backlash and the different Christian churches united under a single strong leader to fight this threat. Meanwhile, an agency is using these gifted few in the best way possible: To let people with way too much money get a second chance at life by having someone die in their stead. It's a bit complicated, but that's the gist of it.</p>

<p>The main character is filled with snark, to a large extent as a defense mechanism against a world that hates her for what she is while coveting the services she can provide. She is backed up by hot boytoy Lane and her best friend Ally (with the inevitable triangle drama), and things are going fairly normally ...</p>

<p>Until it no longer does. She finds herself being questioned over a murder---her own, to be precise---and gets implicated in the murder of her abusive stepfather. Meanwhile, someone's still trying to kill her---as they've killed several others like her---and she needs to sort out the emotions in her little triangle drama. What exactly is going on, and is she going crazy?</p>

<p>Though the premise is quite interesting, the book takes quite some time to get going, while simultaneously trying to do too much, explain too much, in too short a period of time. When I finally really got into it, I read two more pages and ended up staring at the back cover, which was a bit disappointing.</p>

<p>It's written all in first person, and occasionally Jesse's voice is grating, at least for me. I think the main time it really bugged me was a sex scene between her and Lane, where it was too clinical to be titillating, while simultaneously making me feel like I shouldn't be reading it in public. It was a very strange juxtaposition!</p>

<p>In the end, I think it's a decent book. If the subject matter---living-dead agents trying to uncover a conspiracy---seems interesting, it's worth a read as origin story for the second book. I did read the first chapter of the second book, and the pace seems to pick up quite a lot.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1136</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-03-03 18:49:13]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-03-03 16:49:13]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[dying-living]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[by Kory M. Shrum]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Antipathia</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/antipathia/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 17:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1142</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/media/antipathia-cover-682x1024.jpg" alt="Antipathia Cover" width="682" height="1024" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1132" /></p>

<p><strong>Stars: 5</strong></p>

<h2>Review</h2>

<p>Never have I been happier to not see a book written in first person! Talitha Curie is, frankly, not a very likable person. She is an angsty teenager who's completelly contrary with edges in every direction. That's part of the charm of this book, though I'm glad it starts off with action in the first chapter. That, to me, buys the time for the author to make us start caring about Tal before things <em>really</em> get twisted.</p>

<p>The cast is interesting, from the overly chipper Danielle with her strong faith, through the mysterious (and really cute) Christophe and the frail Miranda who might collapse at a stiff breeze. I like the feeling of otherness</p>

<p>My main complaint about it? It was too short! I could've continued reading about them for several more thousand words after the story was finished, and it finished as strongly as it started. A real supernatural story drawing on elements of legends while putting its' own twist to it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1142</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-03-03 19:06:56]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-03-03 17:06:56]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[antipathia]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[by Cee Martinez]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Plottings</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/plottings/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 17:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1150</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Shards of a Bygone Era <small>(Skärvor av det Förgångna)</small></h2>

<p>Vendela Frid is a modern woman with a modern, logical mind. She has little patience with moon-eyed guys who insist she needs to be <em>emotional</em> and talk about her <em>feelings</em>. Her best friend in the whole world is Sia Starholm, who she's shared adventures with in the forest and mountains outside of the family's farm since third grade. Where Vendela is controlled, Sia is on the ditzier side, and that one dimple (in her right cheek) is rarely far away.</p>

<p>By pure coincidence, this journalist student meets a prince---almost literally, his grandmother is a Russian princess in exile---with money to burn. At that particular time he was burning it at the burlesque club where she dances for extra money during her studies, as one of <em>his</em> old friends had a bachelor party.</p>

<p>Andrej Volonskij is a playboy. He is a professional company owner and investor who uses money gotten from ... well, it's not exactly <em>known</em> where they came from originally, to invest in startups and others that are big on ideas and low on capital. When he is in Stockholm, the catlike Katja---aspiring designer for the stars---is rarely far from his arms, and when he's not, he still rarely lacks for female companionship.</p>

<p>That is, of course, until an ice queen crosses his path and a dangerous game begins. Though they aren't aware of it, something sinister is watching, and as a predator recognizes another, a centuries-old serial killer realises that his prey is about to become someone elses.</p>

<p>In the end, Vendela needs to learn to harness the ancient magics she unknowingly is the heir to, to be able to bring retribution and defeat the threat once and for all. Harder still, she needs to face the one thing that might destroy her for good: Her own emotions.</p>

<h2>Blood sisters <small>(Blodsystrar)</small></h2>

<p>Sia Starholm is cheerfully living off of a small inheritance. She spends most of her time trying to figure out what she wants to do next, and how she and her on-again-off-again girlfriend Katja will sort things out---if they can, that is. Her BFF Vendela is still coping with her PTSD, but things are getting easier. Besides, she had Vendela's back during the 'worst', and now her sister---in all senses but the biological one---is feeling so much better, so she's not going to abandon her.</p>

<p>Back "in the day", Sia and her mother moved to a settlement outside of Tanumshede. Sia's mother had filed a restraining order against Sia's father, and they were trying to start anew. For Sia, it worked out well. She met Vendela and they were soon best of friends, and in Vendela's grandparents she found the loving parents she never had at home.</p>

<p>In fact, while her mother Yvonne drank, did drugs and went from boyfriend to boyfriend in an attempt to forget about her ex, Sia spent most of her time on the farm, helping Bertil and Elis. She rarely thought about her father, and she refused to call any of the boyfriends dad.</p>

<p>Now to actual plot: Sia's father has found her. The story will focus on Sia finding out her own past (which I haven't figured out yet, either), and how it interacts with Vendela, her non-biological sister. Maybe she has other sisters too? Is he the violent bastard that Yvonne claims? Is Yvonne's claims actually false, and she had other motives (or reasons) to file the restraining order? Or did she see something she shouldn't have? We'll find out!</p>

<h2>Overarching metaplot</h2>

<p>Both stories draw heavily the Swedish folklore, maybe harking back to Norse mythology. I spent my summers outside of Tanumshede, I currently work in Stockholm. I love the beautiful nature and the mystique of the forests and mountains and oceans.</p>

<p><a href="https://play.spotify.com/user/11127868775/playlist/12zKSliQbaqvPIrpyxRiHK">Spotify playlist</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1150</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-03-10 19:03:07]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-03-10 17:03:07]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[plottings]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Teaser</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/teaser/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 16:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marie]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1167</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new WIP has presented itself to me. Parts of it I've been working through in other ways, but I restarted the idea, trying to use the <a href="http://www.advancedfictionwriting.com/articles/snowflake-method/">Snowflake method</a> to see how that works out for me.</p>

<p>This is going to be the first in an epic fantasy YA story set in a world of myths and legends. It follows a young Jarl, Vanlandi, and his wife Lynessa, as they quest to save their world from eternal darkness. All teasers are from different parts of the process, though will be occasionally revised once the stories are.</p>

<h2>Descriptions</h2>

<h3>Vanlandi</h3>

<p>Tall, especially for his age, with broad shoulders. He is toned and curvy, with ruddy, weatherworn skin. His eyes are a dark, deep blue, which shifts into tones of grey when he's angry. His dark honey blond hair hangs down below his shoulders: straight with a few braids to keep it in place. As he prefers to not show of his peaked hairline, it's rarely pulled back completely. His face is square, with a beaked nose, cleft chin and high cheekbones. A slender scar crosses his left eyebrow, sewn t together with crude stitches. His gaze under blond eyebrows flickers around any area he is in, with every movement conserving energy and preparing for a yet-unknown ambush.</p>

<h3>Lynessa</h3>

<p>She is slender and lithe, with hair that shifts in bands of red and brown and hangs down her back in thick curls. Her face is pale with expressive, dark eyebrows and long, black eyelashes that contrast against hazel eyes shifting in dark green and gold. With high cheekbones that are touched by pink and a slight chin she has a fragile and delicate appearance.</p>

<h2>Vanlandi Sveigdersson, of Yngling line</h2>

<p>Born to Sveigder Fjolnersson and Vana Eorundsdottir I was my father's desperately longed for son. He taught me all he could, raising me a hunter, a warrior, a tactician. I was barely sixteen winters when a stray boar skewered him during a hunt, leaving me Jarl of the Ynglingaline.</p>

<p>We had enemies, many who would do anything to destroy us. One of them, unfortunately, was my own uncle, Agne Eorundsson. He had never forgiven my father for taking my mother. As if he had any say in the path of a man to his woman! Another enemy was that Lowlander king, Alderan of Keer, whose father Amalric my father killed in war. Any sign of weakness on my part and the wolves would feast. I would not, could not, allow that.</p>

<p>Alderan of Keer had a daughter, Lynessa. I had seen her as I scried using the Mirror in my keep. Peasants might get away with stealing their brides from their neighbours with only a few buddies to stop them from taking their price, but I was a Jarl. Only the most dangerous heists would do, so I gathered twenty of my best warriors in a raid on Haith, the capital of Keer. The Wild Hunt rode again, and I came back victorious with my bride. She was a strange one, though. Seeing me without clothes on she called me a woman, as if my body would decide that!</p>

<p>I had even before I took her decided that we would not be intimate, not that soon. Since she was not used to our customs, it was better to wait until she was more used to her own position in my magical Keep, carved out of the glacier we make our home, high up in the North, above the Lowlands.</p>

<p>We were the only ones who could tame the mares and stallions of the icy winds, and the Keep was my ancestral home. No other tribes have ever found a gem such as it, and it's worth defending until death. Unfortunaly, war wasn't the only defense we need to mount. We also had to play politics. A good thing my mother was a Vala. She had trained me in things my warrior father never learned---never had any need to learn ---as he could take anyone in even an unfair fight.</p>

<p>Then, as if we needed more complications, we saw the Rider's horse falter. The Wolf saw its' chance, and then the Sun-Child was gone. I I could only do one thing: I set the Council to keep the clan together and prepared to find the Sun-Child and the Wolf, to save our worlds from endless darkness. The Runes demanded I not go alone, and they also named my companion: My wife. Wonderful. How could I do what I needed to if I was needing to slow down to let her keep up? At least she knew how to ride, though she'd never ridden a stallion, especially not one as powerful as our horses.</p>

<p>Our first stop on the way was to quest through the Far Country. That is the land of fairy tales, bound by rules strange to most. We met the Nornir, finally, the Three who see what Was, what Is, and what Should be. They, too, are bound by their nature, and their nature demanded we both be tried in Trials Three. Waiting for Lynessa to finish hers was a nightmare. She had made it quite clear that she didn't want to be my wife, so I knew I had to let her go. No one would worry about my first wife once the Sun-Child was back, so I would not lose face in letting her return to her people. My heart, maybe, but I was a Jarl. Sacrifices need to be made to keep strength.</p>

<p>The Norns could not tell us where the Wolf lay, only that the one who could know was the Morrigan, bound into a Sword by a king before a battle years ago, long before I or Lynessa were born. She, however, recognized the story. The king was her grandfather Amalric of Keer, which meant I knew which battle the Norns were talking about: The one where my father killed him. Apparently binding an ancient portent of War and Death into a sword doesn't in fact save you from your fate.</p>

<p>I don't do groveling. I certainly don't do subtlety, but I understood that we needed diplomacy to be able to get the Mirror of the Morrigan from Alderan. It would've helped if Lynessa had told me how crazy her father was, since he apparently wanted to marry Lynessa. She had mentioned that Lowlanders apparently "arrange" marriages for their children---what a strange concept! Why would you give away a daughter like that? How would you know that the new husband could protect her? ---but it was the first I heard of fathers marrying daughters. So, he told his guards to seize us. I couldn't get away myself, but I made sure that Lynessa did.</p>

<p>Apparently while I was chained up in the dungeon, Lynessa figured out a plan to free me. Not really sure I like being rescued by my wife--- that certainly would not help my reputation---but it's preferrable to being a <em>guest</em> of Alderan's. Together we fled Keer with the bound Morrigan. I knew quite certainly that she would leave us to fend for ourselves if we freed her, and she admitted as much. However, in return for her help she made us swear to free her once we had found the Wolf, which we agreed to.</p>

<p>It wasn't easy. The gods know that. The Wolf laired high up in the North, far beyond places I've ever been. If it hadn't been for our stallions I'm not sure we would have been able to get there, but finally we did. The Wolf attacked us as soon as we entered his cave, which we expected. We won through a drawn-out battle, though even as we stood victorious over the Wolf, that was just the beginning. The child was safe, but the Sun needs the be carried across the sky by the Rider, and the Rider was no where to be found.</p>

<p>And thus, we needed to travel up into the heavens to track down the Rider. At least we had light.</p>

<h2>Lynessa of Keer</h2>

<p>I grew up hearing how beautiful my mother had been. Elaisse her name was, and she died when I was only two years old. My father, Alderan, was the king of Keer, and I his only heir, as he refused to marry anyone that could not match her beauty. When I was fourteen he stopped looking at me like a father looks at his daughter. Thhat's when I started hoping that someone would come and rescue me. I used to look through the window, daydreaming that a stranger would come and sweep me off my feet. When it finally happened it was closer to a nightmare.</p>

<p>While growing up my Nanny used to tell me stories about the Wild Hunt. Barbarians, probably not even human, she said. The were half-human, half-beast, riding on flying horses born out of the North wind. They stole women and children, as well as anything else that wasn't nailed down. They came with the storms, warning all of the danger. I always thought that you'd be safe if you weren't inside, but that's before Vanlandi smashed my window and pulled me out of my tower.</p>

<p>Vanlandi ... I still don't really get it. Things were very simple at home. I expected to be married off to some man, hopefully a fairly young one, and then we'd live together happily. If ... we weren't happy we'd both find ourselves a mistress. That's how things should be. Right? Instead I found myself supposedly married to a smelly barbarian <em>woman</em>, and to make things worse, apparently he's seen as a man to his people. I really wanted someone to come and rescue me, but while waiting I played the Lady of the Keep, since that was what was expected of me. Vanlandi always wanted to be far too direct, but with the Vala's help I could guide ... him. I knew enough about politics from home, even if I hadn't expected to use it that soon.</p>

<p>And then just ... I'd heard legends about the Sun being a child carried across the sky in the arms of the Rider, hunted by a Wolf, but I never thought I'd see that it was the literal truth. The Vala---apparently Vanlandi's mother?---said that I had go with him. I was a little bit excited about that, honestly. I'd gone from my tower to Vanlandi's keep and I was looking forward to see what else there was, even if it was covered in darkness. And the horse! I had ridden a few times at home, but that was on a gentle little mare. The stallion I was given was huge! I slowly learned to know him though, and he is a darling when given the chance.</p>

<p>Before we left, the Vala brought me to the Crone's Council. They told me about magic, about the path to the Far Country, and that it would be me to lead us into the Far Country itself, since I was a woman, and magic is nothing for a man. Weird, really. Of course it is, everyone knows that only men should do magic; women are too gentle creatures to struggle with the forces of nature like that. But since they told me what to do, I remembered it.</p>

<p>I guess that Vanlandi really is a nice guy. He liked to tease me by kissing my neck, but he'd made it clear that very first night that he wouldn't touch me against my will. I think I hurt him, though. I didn't want to like him, so every time he tried to be nice I rebuffed him. Until he stopped, and I kind-of realised how much I'd liked it. And him.</p>

<p>At any rate, we travelled through the fairy tale land of the Folk, questing for the Nornir. They refused to help us unless we were willing to go through three trials each. I think the one thing that really stuck with me was their defense on why: Because they are bound to their nature.</p>

<p>Turns out, we had to go back home. I had to face my father, with a husband. He reacted ... predictably. At first he pretended to listen, but soon he ordered his guards to arrest us. Vanlandi was his normal heroic self and threw himself in the way, yelling at me to get out, so I ran.</p>

<p>I had to do something. At first I waited, hoping someone would help me, and then it occured to me. I'd spent my entire life waiting for someone to save me. It's the way I was raised, of course, but I shouldn't keep thinking that way. I'd seen the Vala. I'd seen the way that Vanlandi acted. I realised that though the Nornir were bound by their own nature, I was not. I was not bound by anything. I found my old Nanny and asked her to help me. We made a plan, I snuck in, rescued Vanlandi and grabbed the sword. I don't think that Vanlandi liked it too much, and I'm not sure how to tell him why. That I did it because I like him, and that I don't actually want to leave him anymore.</p>

<p>It was really hard to follow the Morrigan's directions. Cold, dark and far outside of any kind of civilization. The Morrigan taught me how to fight a bit, and Vanlandi did too. Turns out that in the end, finding the Wolf wasn't the end of our quest. It was the beginning.</p>

<p>On the plus side? With the Sun-Child free, we have light!</p>

<h2>Vana Eorundsdottir, of Ylfing line</h2>

<p>Sveigder was twice my age, but the moment I saw him I knew I wanted him and no one else. My own parents died when I was three years old, and I rarely saw my older brother, Agne. I think Agne had intended to make sure that whoever stole me from my family would be someone of his choosing, but he learned the hard way that women are not merchandise or commodities to be bargained with.</p>

<p>Of course, I wasn't Sveigder's first wife. I was the first one to bear him a child, though. His first wife---the love of his youth---died in consumption only a few years after they married. Then he married Ketilriðr. She was widowed to one of his warriors, but she was unable to give him the child he needed. They parted ways aimably, but I'm fairly certain she hated me. Anyways, my brother was celebrating the birth of his firstborn the year I turned sixteen. He'd made sure I was prettied up for ... whomever he had decided would make a suitable man for me. Instead, I made sure Sveigder saw me. Saying farewell in the evening he dragged me up his horse before Agne could even react. I knew my brother was weak, and he hated Sveigder for it.</p>

<p>In his keep I had my first vision. I was chosen to speak for the spirits, granting me the title of 'Vala'. When I gave Sveigder the child he'd longed for I prayed that the spirits would name it a son, and they did. Sveigder finally had the heir he wanted and deserved.</p>

<p>It hurt so much when he died. I'd never imagined it. But at least I knew that Vanlandi would be able to handle it; he was born to be a leader. I took a step back, as it is traditional of the old Jarl's widow, hiding myself behind being the Vala. We as a people are proud, and we do not grieve in public.</p>

<p>I was concerned when Vanlandi choose Lynessa as his wife. I understood and agreed with the politics behind it---it showed that he was not one to be trifled with---but she was young and innocent, and she didn't understand our culture. Without letting her know who I was, I made sure to present myself as a trusted ally. I encouraged her friendship with the servant girl Serria, and I listened to her concerns while guiding her through how to be the Jarl's wife. To her credit, she was a natural Lady of the Keep. I also saw how my son fell in love with her, and her falling in love with him, and that both of them were too proud. I think Vanlandi was afraid to scare her off, since she was a bit of a delicate flower, and she didn't want to admit that she preferred her life with us to her life at home.</p>

<p>When the Sun was stolen, Vanlandi didn't have a choice. We both knew that. An army wouldn't help, but I hoped that a single young woman might. We'll see if she'll grow with the responsibility I and the Crones put on her slender shoulders.</p>

<h2>Agne Eorundsson, of Ylfing line</h2>

<p>Disrespectful simpletons all! Sveigder was always a boisterous and loud man. I tolerated him because of his power, and because the Ice Keep Tribe were in a better position than mine was. I had intended to make sure that I tied the Folkung to us by having their Jarl take my sister.</p>

<p>My parents died when I was nineteen years old, and I took over the tribe as its' Jarl. I had plans to grow our strength, though unfortunately some of those plans hinged on the mewling brat that was my younger sister growing up. She filled up nicely, though, so the year she turned sixteen it was time. It luckily coincided with the birth of my daughter Sòlveig to my Skjalf, so I had a good excuse to arrange festivities.</p>

<p>You can imagine my humiliation as Sveigder Fjolnersson grabbed my sister as he left. She held onto him, giving me a triumphant look as they rode off on his great white stallion. I can never live down the shame of not even having enough warning to try to ward off my sister's suitor. People laugh at me behind my back. What kind of man would not be able to defend their own family? Curse Sveigder, and curse my sister!</p>

<p>I was certain that I would get my chance to take charge of the tribe when Sveigder met his death at the end of a wild boar's skewering. After all, my nephew Vanlandi was barely sixteen winters old. He surprised me, though. I never expected him to be that worthy an adversary. I was expecting to win, however, despite that young thing he took as his.</p>

<p>And then darkness. My revenge would have to wait. Armies can not be launched in the night.</p>

<h2>Serria</h2>

<p>Me? I'm just a peasant girl. Third child of five. We were dirt poor, and my parents were just looking for a man to unburden them of me when I did something that I'm still not sure if it was a mistake or the best thing I could've done: I fell asleep outside.</p>

<p>When I woke up, a sudden storm had hit us, and I fought to find my way home. Before I could get into the safety of our little hut I heard the whinny of a horse and was scooped up on a giant stallion by a furred creature. Or, as it turned out, by a warrior in a heavy cloak. He pulled me against him, making sure I was bundled up against the cold.</p>

<p>His name was Aghi. Apparently he had seen me outside a few times and wanted me as his. I could certainly have done worse. He never hit me, he didn't drink himself into a stupor and he was a good provider. I think that's why I wanted to comfort Princess Lynessa when she came to the keep. She was terrified, and a bit naive. Considering how she was raised, probably not too surprising. She seemed to be looking for someone to rescue her.</p>

<p>The dowager queen---though they don't call her that, I'm not sure what the difference between her title and that of a queen would be---was a very kind woman, though stern. She made sure that Princess Lynessa and I could have a friendship which I think we both needed. Even with Aghi and the littles I occasionally felt like a stranger here.</p>

<h2>The Nornir</h2>

<h3>Urthr, Skuld and Verthandi</h3>

<p>We are the Nornir. We see what was, what is, and what must happen. Know that there is a difference between what <em>must</em> happen and what <em>will</em> happen. You are not bound by fate in your actions. However, what must happen is that Lynessa finds the strength within to save Vanlandi in his day of need, and that they both agree to deal given to them by the Morrigan. If not, they will perish, and the hopes of man will become futile.</p>

<h2>Alderan of Keer</h2>

<p>When my father, Amalric of Keer, showed me the miniature of my future wife I immediately fell in love with her. Elaisse was such a lovely creature. Gentle, beautiful. I could never imagined marrying another woman, despite her not having given me an heir. That is, until I saw Lynessa grow into womanhood, the spitting image of her mother. Then I knew that I had to marry her. It was the final gift from my beloved.</p>

<p>Then she was taken from me again. Kidnapped from the very tower I had locked her in to ensure she was safe. By the same despicable creatures that killed my father. Of course, they had been in league with the Morrigan, of that I'm certain. Why else would she have spoken of our defeat?</p>

<p>My father knew how to deal with that kind of ilk, though. She had come on his bidding, but when she told him that what she saw was his destruction he had her arrested and her spirit bound into a Sword for him to bring with him as we faced off against the so-called Wild Hunt. We would have won, too, had not the Sword turned against him. I saw how the leader of the Hunt killed my father. I swore to destroy them for that, and then they took my beloved daughter.</p>

<p>Then the darkness struck. All I could do was to try to keep the country together. Imagine my shock when Lynessa returned, and with <em>that</em>. My beautiful daughter, daring to bring into my home a barbarian, one of the creatures who'd killed my father. In fact, the son of my father's killer. She called herself his wife, and they talked about the Sword. Something delusional about the darkness and it being due to the mythical Wolf. Seeing my chance to bring her back I ordered my guards to seize the monster. It hurt me that Lynessa rather than taking the chance to come back home fled.</p>

<p>She must have been brainwashed by the barbarians, because she wasn't the gentle woman I had raised, but rather a sassy one that spoke back. She had been destroyed.</p>

<h2>The Morrigan</h2>

<p>You know who I am. I am the Morrigan, queen of war and strife. While my sisters, the Nornir, speak of what was, what is and what should be, I only see what will be: Who will die, who will win, who will stand victorious as the bloody mists water the ground. In fact, who will stand at all.</p>

<p>Many years ago, per the counting of mortals, I was summoned to council a King of the Lowlands, in the country of Keer. He was fated to die at the hand of Sveigder of the North, and I told him as much. He did not appreciate my council. I believe he thought that his death meant the death of his kingdom. A foolish man, Amalric of Keer. He believed he could intimidate me.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I underestimated his perseverance. He bound me with Magic of Iron into a sword which he mockingly called the Mirror of Morrigan. How I detested that man. Uncouth, uncivilized, unmannered. He brought me with him when he tried to invade the northern glaciers, but he learned that it's complicated when your opponents have flying horses.</p>

<p>I killed in his name, while biding my time. Finally I saw him: Sveigder Fjolnersson. He fought bravely, and I guided him closer. The battle was magnificent, and though Sveigder's sword broke in his hands he fought on. Amalric lost his grip on me, and Sveigder took me, giving me my revenge. Perhaps things would have ended up differently if not Alderan had come to his father's defense, driving off Sveigder and his kinsmen in frenzied rage. Or maybe not. Perhaps this is what was bid to happen.</p>

<p>I fell asleep waiting to be freed, and then I was awoken by Vanlandi. I would known him everywhere, he is surprisingly like his father. Also, where Amalric was delusional, I believe that Vanlandi isn't. He also doesn't need my help, which is why I ensured that Lynessa wielded me. The little one is not as much of a wishy-washy airhead as she might come off as, but she needs help to mature into that which she is fated to become. Her father might have doted on her in his sick desire for her, but he did not do her any favours.</p>

<h2>The Huntress</h2>

<p>Let me tell you a story.</p>

<p>Once upon a time---and why no one knows---the Rider scooped up Sunne, the Sun-Child in its' arms. On Skinfaxi they started riding across the sky. In hot pursuit came Skoll, a giant Wolf intent on swallowing the child whole. Perhaps the Rider had offended the Wolf? No one knows why Skoll hates the Rider and Sunne so much, but we could not let the Wolf destroy this youngest of our Celestials.</p>

<p>We were the Star-Maidens, who give light during the night. Sunne shines the brightest of all of us, and through her ride across the sky, she grants that light to the worlds below. My light is nearly as strong, and my skills with the spear superior to anyone else. So, therefor, I chose to mount Hrimfaxi and pursue the Wolf. We ride in perfect harmony over the sky, and every so often I come closer, hiding my light under my hood, before the Rider finds new strength and we are once again off.</p>

<p>Every night my sisters help me light up the night, and every day I rest as Sunne lights up the day, banishing all that is dark. That is, until something quite unexpected happened: Skinfaxi faltered.</p>

<p>That should never have happened again. But because it did, the Wolf saw its' chance, and snatched Sunne out of the arms of the Rider, snuffing out the light of day.</p>

<p>At first we reeled. I knew that I should go after Skoll, but if I did, how would the worlds get any light? I saw the Rider flee deep into the darker corners of the sky, and all I could do was hope that one of the mortals would be strong enough to take up the mantle. I sent out the call for my sisters to scour the worlds for that one hero. One by one they sent me messages stating that the Lowlanders lacked such heroes. So did the Far Country, and all the other countries. I had almost given up in despair when a little boy came flying. He spoke of a Jarl, Vanlandi of the line of Yngling, of the frozen North, of the Wild Hunt. He had travelled out with his wife, Lynessa of Keer, a Lowlander. As much as I wanted to do something, I knew that it was in the hands of the Nornir, but I ensured that there would be someone always keeping an eye on the development.</p>

<p>I knew that the Lowlanders had stopped "believing" in us. Their strange new advisors were speaking of Science, of us not existing, so it did not surprise me that they did nothing. The people of the Far Country are too bound by their own laws to be able to act. The only one with enough power to break out of that mold is the Morrigan, and she disappeared from our view many years ago</p>

<p>From time to time I was given reports that Vanlandi and Lynessa were moving forward. They found their way through the tasks set before them, and they even found the Morrigan. I made sure to get closer to Skoll's cave as they did, since I knew that they would get there. I waited, ready to step in, but letting them take the fight. After all, I knew something they didn't: Their task would not be done through the Wolf being defeated. They would need to rise higher, find their way through the world of the Celestials. Maybe even find the secret hidden in Millennia: Who is the Rider?</p>

<h2>Ansgot, son of Wy, Captain of the Royal Guard</h2>

<p>Ï am Ansgot, son of Wy and Hadwisa. My father was a mercenary during the wars that Amalric of Keer started against, among others, the southern reaches. During one of the raids he found my mother and brought her back as a price, since he was high enough ranked that he could afford supporting a concubine. He once told me that his biggest regret was that he could not marry my mother, but it was just not done.</p>

<p>While I grew up I was tormented as a bastard and half-breed, but I learned how to keep my temper. When I was old enough to join the army, I did. I rose through the ranks, especially after saving the life of Prince Alderan. He personally promoted me to Captain of the Guard after his father's death in war, and he's earned my loyalty.</p>

<p>My mother used to warn me about him, though. She said that she saw darkness in him, but I refused to listen. I saw an honourable man, even if he did make mistakes occasionally.</p>

<p>I'm not sure when I realised how far off the deep end he'd gone. Maybe when he started making plans to replace his dead wife with his daughter. I certainly saw it when darkness hit. He didn't know how to deal with it, understandably, but he shut himself in his keep and refused to listen to his people. And then Princess Lynessa returned, with her husband.</p>

<p>He ordered us to seize the ... boy, and we did. He ordered us to throw him into the dungeons, and we did. I ordered the guards to not lay a finger on the young Jarl, at least for now. There is no honour in torture, especially not of a prisoner of war.</p>

<p>It was then that my loyalty and admiration for him died. He tried to stop the two people I'd heard of that were actively trying to restore our world, and for what? His sick desire for his daughter, and a misplace need for retribution over the death of his father, so many years ago.</p>

<p>I have to say that it was strange to see the young princess again. She was very different. More self-assured. Less vapid. That's why, when I heard that she was looking to free her husband, I discreetly made sure that she was aware of my change in allegiance. I may still be punished for it, but I did the right thing, and if I die it is with my conscious clear.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1167</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-04-02 18:01:15]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-04-02 16:01:15]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[teaser]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Harlow Whittaker &amp; the Soothsayers</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/harlow-whittaker-soothsayers/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 16:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1182</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mariehogebrandt.se/assets/media/Print-HW1-Cover.jpg" alt="Harlow Whittaker & the Soothsayers Cover" width="312" height="500" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1184" /></p>

<p><strong>Stars: 4</strong></p>

<h2>Review</h2>

<p>Harlow Whittaker is a spunky nineteen-year-old who prefers sarcasm to letting people in. Her broken heart (due to her ex's inability to accept the vision she had of her dead grandmother when she was twelve) quickly mends as she meets Larken. Can he be more dreamy? Motorcycle, leatherjacket, black angelic wings ...</p>

<p>She is the first human soothsayer, and now she needs to find the other soothsayers, preferrably before one of the myriad of headhunters and other unsavoury creatures gets to her. By her side she has three guardians, known as Archers. Larken can travel through the worlds easier, Fin is a healer, and Hendrix has charms that can do the most impressive things.</p>

<p>Do they reach the Soothsayers? Now, that would be telling!</p>

<p>This is a really good read. A modern fantasy with interesting characters and nicely layered conflicts and action. I recommend it wholeheartedly, as it's very well written. The sequel is coming out in June 2014.</p>

<p>The one thing that lowers the grade from 5 stars down to "only" 4 is that it's lacking some in the editing. The point of views are occasionally a bit strange, and the occasional sentence is a touch awkward. However, don't let that stop you from reading it. Valerie Day-Sánchez spins a very, very vivid world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1182</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-05-07 18:02:17]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-05-07 16:02:17]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[harlow-whittaker-soothsayers]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[by Valerie Day-Sánchez]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Steampunk</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/steampunk/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 04:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1192</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Warning, this is first draft material, and not finished.</strong> Brownie points to anyone who can figure out which span of history this starts in.</p>

<p>The second knock was less patient than the first one. She ignored it, still. Her hands were covered with grime, the humming of the engine interspersed with the clunking of a loose cog. The loose cog she was trying to find, to be exact.</p>

<p>"Augustín!" It was Henry, one of the younger recruits on the Seadragon. "Augustín! The captain wants a word."</p>

<p><em>Right.</em> She shook her head as she crawled back from underneath the heavy machinery, wiping her hands on the towel next to the door. It did little to clean up the oil, but gave her the defense of having tried.</p>

<p>She slipped her bare feet into the heavy boots, pulling a hand through her oily locks. Clonk. Clonk. Clonk. An annoyed glance over at the engine followed by a well-placed fist put the fear of God into the machine.</p>

<p>"Right." She looked over at Henry. He was a gangly youth, gaunt with dirty tests of blonde hair hanging into his blue eyes. "What is this all about, then?" She didn't bother pitching down her voice; no one here would doubt her abilities or question her worth. A grin crossed her features. <em>Not twice, at any rate.</em></p>

<p>"Captain didn't say." He kept his eyes averted. "Just said to get you."</p>

<p>She nodded, following him to the deck. Her balance on the swaying deck was perfect, compensating for the waves. Henry knew how to compensate as well. "You were a fisherman before you were recruited?" Her English melodic, with a hint of the Spanish lilt that betrayed, if her colouring and name didn't, her heritage.</p>

<p>"Yes. Navy ... recruited me first, though." His face darkened. "I prefer the Seadragon."</p>

<p>"I would too." She shrugged, stepping up on deck. Karl Stranne, once of Smögen, steered. The ship followed his every movement. She stole a moment of admiration for the winsome sailor with the steady hands. "Captain, you wanted to see me?" A hint of annoyance in her voice.</p>

<p>He smirked in response. "Agustín, you are not irreplaceable." His afro hair cropped short, the long scar across his face--which had given him the nickname Serendipitous--tugged at his lips.</p>

<p>She grinned, teasingly winking. "Begging you pardon, Captain, but yes, I am." She straightened up. "What can I do for you, Captain?"</p>

<p>François le Fortuite pointed into the distance. She accepted the tube, following the line of a ship with her gaze. "She is taking in water. I don't see any men aboard."</p>

<p>"How long do you think she's got before she goes under?"</p>

<p>"Hard to say, though we should be able to reach her, if that's what you're asking."</p>

<p>"Would she have any of those ... things you're wanting for the engine?" He slipped his thumb into the armpit of his worn vest, his shoulders broad.</p>

<p>"She might." She studied the ship, with doubt creeping into her voice. "It's hard to tell from here. All I can say is that she isn't an ironclad, and you didn't need me to tell you that."</p>

<p>"Hmm." Rubbing his goatee he pursed his lips in thought. She waited patiently. Few men were as good at analyzing a situation correctly with so few facts. "Very well. Go back to your engine. We should reach her in a couple of hours. Be ready for it."</p>

<p>She had barely settled in the parts of the engine that weren't too hot or too dangerous when a knock once again disturbed her concentration.</p>

<p>"What?" She bit back a sharper response.</p>

<p>"Captain says we're approaching the ship." Henry again. Had he been appointed 'first engineer-botherer' when she wasn't looking?</p>

<p>She slid back from underneath the machinery. "Right, I'll be out there in a moment."</p>

<p>This close, the frigate looked even shabbier than she had from the distance. "<em>The Sultry Mermaid</em>" The captain raised an eyebrow, and she nodded towards the name on the side.</p>

<p>"Oh." He shrugged, busying himself with the tube. "Alright, men, she looks abandoned! <em>Allez! Toute de suite!</em>" François lead the charge on the ghost ship. She checked the short sword and the revolver before following him.</p>

<p>The smell of the ocean was heavy on the creaking <em>Mermaid</em>. She sniffed, but it was just rotting wood and seaweed, not rotting flesh. "Henry, on me." Her voice soft as she moved down into the engine room. Water was reaching up to her ankles as she moved through the inside of the ship. The cold was numbing, and she checked her sword by pure instinct.</p>

<p>The shriek of a banshee echoed through the engine room as a ghost attacked her. She stumbled backwards, fumbling to get the ghast off of her. Finding soft fur under her hands she relaxed a touch, especially as the tail was covered in fur as well.</p>

<p>The kitten was soaking wet, which explained the shriek, shaking. She lift it up by the neck ruff and studied it. "Poor thing is starving." Wrapping it up in her bandanna she stuffed the critter into a spare pocket, ignoring its' indignant meowing. "Let's see what else we have here ..."</p>

<hr />

<p>Very little was salvageable, but she'd found a diary and some things that she and Henry had been able to pry off the dead engine. The kitten looked like a black, fluff ball as it lay next to her.</p>

<p>François stepped into her cabin after a quick rap on the door, interrupting her reading. "Anything useful?"</p>

<p>She shook her head. "The diary has some interesting ideas, but I think that the most useful thing is going to be the ship cat." She marked the passage she was on, closing the book. "Did you find anything useful?"</p>

<p>"Some food. They'd cleaned it out fairly well before they left. Did you see any reason why they abandoned ship?"</p>

<p>"Engine was broke, and considering how much water she was taking in ..." She tapped her lower lip. "I've been thinking, Captain ..."</p>

<p>"Do you ever do anything else?" The amused tone taking the sting out of the words.</p>

<p>"Well, I could stop thinking, but then Eduardo would've lost that leg completelly." She winked at him. "Anyways, I've seen some interesting designs, both to speed the engine up--once I finally manage to find what is making that rattling sound--and do you remember seeing that airship prototype I think it would be really really interesting to--"</p>

<p>He put a finger on her lips. "Breathe, Agustín. You know that is your department. Don't do anything too big to the ship without talking to me, <em>ma cherie</em>, but when it's just thinking ..."</p>

<p>She nodded, stretching out her body some. "Very well, Captain. I'll be in here until my watch. I have some things to catch up on."</p>

<p>She looked over at the purring kitten, mussing its' black fur. It nipped at her fingers. She tapped it on the nose, shifting to her native Spanish. "Silly cat. I saved you, remember?" Tugging the cat to her lap, it settled with its' head on her knee, wrapping its' frontpaws around her wrist. "That is making it difficult to read, little one."</p>

<p>The diary was in a legible English print, with only a few smudges and inkblots. In between notes of the daily work were sketches and schematics. "Minerva, I wish I could've talked to this one. He has some brilliant ideas." She flipped to the front. "Vivian Allgood. I shall keep that in mind." The cat purred, a steady vibration.</p>

<p>Together with the content of the diary it helped her shut out the rest of the world. Cogwheels and intricate details of machinery danced alongside sketches of fastenings and sweeping sails formed <em>just so</em>.</p>

<p>Eduardo scurried down the rigging from the crow's nest, hopping like an actual crow. Landing in front of her, the clicking of his mechanical leg sent pleasant shivers up her spine.</p>

<p>"Is it working well?" She nodded towards the leg, speaking in Spanish.</p>

<p>He responded in his native Portuguese, supplemented with a broad grin. "Yes. How did you ..." waving his hand, adding in English. "Make it move?"</p>

<p>"Simple. Just a matter of ..." At Eduardo's blank stare she shrugged. "<em>Ciencia</em>"</p>

<p>He flashed a grin that exposed broken and missing teeth. His gait not as graceful on the deck, the clicking and whirring of the cogwheels as they kept up with his movements more pronounced; keeping the foot parallel to the dock in the rolls of the ship.</p>

<p>She stretched out in the crow's nest, before settling down. Long, mind-numbing hours of staring out over the sea, glittering in gold and oranges as the sun set, awaited her. Dividing her thoughts into the part that had to--and did--watch for signs of trouble or profit, and the part that soared like the albatrosses above. A small bird hopped across the water, then another of the same species. And another one. Mother Carey's Chickens!</p>

<p>The tube confirmed the warning, supplemented by the scent of the approaching storm. She rang the bell, for once not paying attention to the sweet tone as it rang across the deck. Hopping down, François met her below.</p>

<p>"How bad?" Scratching his shoulder.</p>

<p>"Bad." She held out the tube. He cursed. The sky was black at the horizon.</p>

<p>As François started barking out orders, she sprinted to the engine room. "Come on, come on ..."</p>

<p>They had enough time to prepare, and once Agustín felt secure in the engine not breaking in the heavy movements she sprinted back up on deck, wrapped up in an oilskin coat and heavy boots.</p>

<p>Even through that she was soon drenched once the storm hit. The sails were secured, and as much as they could--including Karl Stranne, the pilot--was tied down. Only way to weather a storm this big was to ride it out.</p>

<p>"Agustín, to me!" François bellowed through the raging storm. The deck was almost empty, leaving the skeleton of a crew necessary to keep her steady. A sudden wave shook the deck and she stumbled.</p>

<p>"Yes, Captain?" The wind stealing the words, another wave washing over the deck. She kept the grip on the railing ropes.</p>

<p>"If anyone can ride her out, it's Karl. We're trailing as much as we can. If the storm gets heavier ..."</p>

<p>"I will put the engines in reverse at your order, Captain." Wrapping another rope around her arm. "With the modi--"</p>

<p>"Not now, <em>ma chérie</em>." He held up a hand. "I still need your watchful eyes."</p>

<p>A scream resounded through the storm. The hairs on her body rose and she blinked away tears. François lips were moving in prayer, and she joined him, though his was in French and hers in Spanish. "<em>Dios te salve, María, llena eres de gracia ...</em>" As earnestly as Doña Agustína Maria de la Soledad had prayed in the chapel of her father's estate, did Agustín on the deck of a pirate ship. Far from home, far from hearth, far from the life she had been raised to lead.</p>

<hr />

<p>The morning found them far from their regular route. Agustín stumbled up to help untie Karl from the steering wheel. They were both as soaking wet, but he more exhausted. Miguel, a wiry countryman of Eduardo, replaced him in the calmer winds.</p>

<p>Karl and Agustín supported each other, moving down under deck. Every face she saw gave her comfort. She blinked away tears at the once she didn't see. "Bert?"</p>

<p>Eduardo shook his head, grimacing. "And Boniface. May their souls rest in peace."</p>

<p>Her mind numb from the storm she could but nod, heading to her own cabin. Stripping out of the oilskin coat and boots, she curled up in her cot as she was. It never did get easier to lose friends, be it to storms, battles or disease.</p>

<p>"What's the damage?" She strode up to François. He gave her a tired look, rubbing his goatee.</p>

<p>"Half the fresh water supply. Thanks to good warning from you, not much worse than that." Though he did not mention Bert or Boniface, he didn't need to. "We are still trying to figure out exactly where we are."</p>

<p>"I'll be in the engine room." As she turned, he placed a hand on her shoulder.</p>

<p>"Agustín. We will have a ceremony to honour our lost once we've found our bearings."</p>

<p>She mustered up a hesitant smile, barely nodding as she slunk off.</p>

<p>Minerva found her in the engine room. Her tail was tall, the airs clearly marking her as mistress of the ship. Agustín smiled, petting her soft head. "Hello little one. Exploring your new domains?" The cat flicked her tail, buffing her head against the dirty hand. "Be careful around her. There's plenty of places a little cat can get caught."</p>

<p>Minerva froze, staring into a corner. Agustín squinted, following the cat's gaze. A movement, and then Minerva was off. "Of course. There's also rats."</p>

<p>"Are you talking to yourself?" François amused voice caught her off guard. She changed to English.</p>

<p>"No, to the cat. A proper mouser, by the look of things. Let's hope the ship rats aren't going to be the masters of her."</p>

<p>"It's a cat." He shrugged. "How's the engine looking?"</p>

<p>"A bit wet--some of the water came in here--but nothing worse than that." She tapped the engine a moment. "Do you need Henry?"</p>

<p>His eyebrows raised. "Do I want to know why you're asking that?"</p>

<p>She rolled her eyes, chuckling. "Get your mind out of the gutter, François. I could do with someone smaller to help me." She raised her hand, forestalling his question. "And no, the cat won't be enough. For one, I don't think I can train her to tell me what is wrong where I can't reach."</p>

<p>"Well, I will send him here <em>toute de suite</em>. When we reach port next, if he is not good enough ..."</p>

<p>"We will find someone there." She nodded. "For now he is."</p>

<p>Henry gave her an apprehensive and diffident look as he slunk into the engine room. "You ... had need of me?"</p>

<p>"Yes. Have you ever worked with an engine before?"</p>

<p>"No ... We had only sails, and the Navy wouldn't let me near the engine, even if I wanted to." Fidgeting under her sharp gaze.</p>

<p>"Good. Then I'll just start from the beginning."</p>

<p>Under his dazed attention she went through what they could see of the engines, explaining each piece. Finally he held up his hands; a shield against the torrent of English mixed with Spanish.</p>

<p>"Please, Agustín ... I don't understand half of this. It might as well be Greek. Or, well." He flashed her a brief grin. "Spanish."</p>

<p>"Philistine." She grinned in return. "Spanish is the language of the Queen. May she return to her throne."</p>

<p>He chuckled. "I think <em>my</em> Queen would disagree." His blue-grey eyes flashed with mirth. She chuckled, nodding lightly.</p>

<p>"Very well, I will try to explain it in an easier way." She was unable to stop herself. "So that even an English mind can understand."</p>

<hr />

<p>She stood up on deck, watching the island approach. François stood at the wheel, proud and strong even as grief muted the humour in his dark eyes.</p>

<p>"Henry!"</p>

<p>"Aye Captain?" The youngster straightened up from his lounging.</p>

<p>"Have you ever sounded a ship into safety by yourself? No? Alright. Agustín, show Henry how to sound using your contraption. I want plenty of warning."</p>

<p>"Aye Captain." She fetched the half-mechanical prototype, walking with the rolling gait of someone used to compensate for the waves. Henry wached her curiously while she showed how to use it.</p>

<p>"I don't get you."</p>

<p>She raised an eyebrow at him. "Oh? What is it you don't get?"</p>

<p>"Just ... you're a woman!"</p>

<p>She didn't bother denying it. "I would be careful with who you said such things to. Now pay attention."</p>

<p>"Yes, but ... Ow!" The back of her hand clipped him over the forehead.</p>

<p>"That was a warning blow. You see this dial here?"</p>

<p>François watched their exchange, a flicker of sardonic amusement, his hands light on the wheel.</p>

<p>The Seadragon danced along the glittering waves. Above them seagulls laughed and screeched; as if the storm of the night had never happened, or maybe that the world had washed its' hands of it. Under Agustín's watchful eyes, Henry called out the depths he read on the contraption.</p>

<p>Once they'd dropped anchors and steadied the ship, François called all sailors onto deck.</p>

<p>"Three groups. Two to explore, one to stay on the ship. Each leader has a horn. Normal signals: two short for danger, three long for water or other resource."</p>

<p>Agustín led one of the two expeditions, her mind wandering as they rowed to the small island. Miguel threw her a glance.</p>

<p>"What's on your mind?"</p>

<p>She blinked out of her reverie. "Something I saw in the diary we found. Trying to figure out if we could make the Seadragon fly."</p>

<p>"Fly?" He blinked, repeating it in English. "Make the ship fly?"</p>

<p>"Well, the theory is sound." She shrugged. "Not with wings. With some kind of big balloon, anchored to ... most likely the railing."</p>

<p>He threw his hands out in an apologetic gesture. "I don't know <em>ciência</em>."</p>

<p>The banter lightened her heart, even as she tensed. There was something ... She forestalled more comments with a raised hand. Her lips parted as she tried to localize the source of unease.</p>

<p>"Ambush! Back to the ship!" Blowing the horn twice. Another ironclad, under sail to stay silent, rounded the island. The brief scent of fuel permeated the air again, as they rowed under curses. The flag of Spain waved proudly from the rigging. <em>Carlists. Was this a stroke of bad luck, or had they been trying to find the Seadragon?</em></p>

<p>Waves from the larger ironclad pummeled the row boats. They had gotten farthest away from the Seadragon, so to her gratitude the other sailors were climbing up the side. A shot whizzed through the air. Again the Seadragon rocked. The last thing she remembered was flying through the air and into the cold water. One of the oars hit her, and unconscious blackness took her.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1192</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-05-23 06:31:06]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-05-23 04:31:06]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[steampunk]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Agustín of the Seadragon]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>How do I description?</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/description/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 18:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1201</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There was a conversation on twitter today about descriptions, and how people describe characters.</p>

<p>To get an interesting view of how different people describe, we decided to start with a common archetype and go wild. All the descriptions will be posted on either blogs (tweet links to @melindrea82), or if necessary could be e-mailed to me and I'll post them here.</p>

<h2>Rules</h2>

<ul>
<li>No more than 500 words, the focus is on how you'd describe a character, not plot</li>
<li>Any PoV and tense, use what's comfortable</li>
<li>Indiana Jones expy/stunt double (so not necessarily Harrison Ford, but in that area)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Participants</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.demerybunn.com/blog/">D. Emery Bunn</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1201</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-07-09 20:11:07]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-07-09 18:11:07]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[description]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Småty</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/smaty/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 15:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1206</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These are the summaries for four (or so ...) books revolving around Swedish folklore. Småty is a collection term for the various supernatural critters, from Bohuslän, which is where most of the books take place.</p>

<h2>Vendela's story</h2>

<p>While dancing at her part-time job (a burlesque strip club in Stockholm), journalism student Vendela meets the rich playboy Andrej, who is immediately smitten with the enticing, chilly blonde. In his pursuit of her, the paparazzi gets a perfect shot of the two dancing, which triggers the instincts of a stalker intent of owning Vendela body and soul. Struggling with connecting the dots between her nightmares, a brutal murder and her increasingly possessive stalker, she is faced with the prospect that it might be Andrej who is behind all of it. Putting her journalistic abilities to the test, she follows him through Stockholm, until they are both faced with the true menace: an immortal mage who kills magical women to gain their powers; the same person who murdered her parents, sending her into the darkest, most damaged recesses of her broken mind. Finally having accepted the truth about magic and her role in things, Vendela takes her new-found knowledge, partial stability and shapeshifting boyfriend to face Blutwald, banishing him and freeing his victims forever.</p>

<h2>Sia's &amp; Katja's story</h2>

<p>Vendela's best friend (and sister-in-spirit) Sia returns to the west coast of her childhood after a particularly strong argument with her girlfriend Katja (Andrej's ex-firlfriend) in an attempt to find peace and balance. Her absent father shows up at her doorstep, warning her that one of his enemies, the Storsjö Monster, is loose and looking for revenge. When the Monster and its pet mage shows up, he falls into slumber due to his wounds, but not before bequeathing Odin's runes to her. Vendela, Andrej and Katja comes at her urging (though Vendela "forgot" to mention that Katja was coming as well), helping her to figure out her new-found magic, but not before the three magical beings are kidnapped by the Monster. Fleeing the scene, Katja stumbles into an old fertility symbol, gaining the powers of a valkyrie, which gives them the edge to destroy the mage through sejd, before once again binding the Monster at the bottom of the lake.</p>

<h2>Cecilia's story</h2>

<p>Traumatised as the sole survivor of Blutwald's depredations--freed from a life as his sexslave by Vendela and Andrej--Cecilia departs a random train at Tanum station, unaware of where she is, struggling with thoughts of self-harm and self-punishment. Malbrecht--a charming Scot with an uncanny ability to show up whenever she least expects him--stops her from committing suicide, and her crippled relationship with him takes a horrifying turn as he is forced into the underworld by his liege Áedan mac Gabráin (d. 606). Cecilia seeks Sia's help, knowing that she is a sejdkona, and is guided into the underworld by the Valkyrie Katja, where she finds out that the she needs to go to Hel to recover the shade of Genovefa mac Cadeyrn--the King's niece. Blutwald bars her from entering Hel's castle, and Katja is not allowed to help her. Fleeing from her tormentor she ends up lost between worlds and is barred from returning until she finds strength in herself to face Blutwald. After all, he's dead; she won. Returning with Genovefa, Áedan is forced to release Malbrecht, but bans him from ever entering Mag Mell again. (Ending uncertain: She might be forced to choose between Malbrecht and returning home, or ending up stuck in the Underworld, or something else. Either way, Malbrecht isn't likely to return at that point.)</p>

<h2>War</h2>

<p>An army is preparing to attack an unaware--and ill-equipped--Sweden, with only a few people ready to stand against it. The first to find out about what is going on is Sia and Katja, living at Greby, as the ghostly army of the Scots sweep through Grebbestad and towards Tanum. Though Greby is safe--if only because they are still ghosts--they know it is only a matter of time before it will manifest, unless they figure out who--or what--is controlling it. Depending on how the prior book ends, Sia either contacts Cecilia and they manage to get Malbrecht back, or the summoning brings both of them back. At any rate, at the battle of Tanum church--once Blodbäck--Malbrecht returns to reclaim the allegiance of his warriors. The necromancer is revealed, but before they can act, he cackles like an old woman. The man has been manipulated by Angerboda, the evil witch, who is using him as a spirit horse. He is the gate between Jotunheim and our plane, and she is now free. Jotuns will soon follow. The protagonists now consist of a dead, Scottish war leader, his 300 ghostly men, a Valkyrie, a wolven shapeshifter, a sejdkona, a skogsrå and a (whatever Cecilia ends up as). That will not last long against the Jotuns, and in desperation they find only once solution: To enter Asgard and plead with the Aesir. Odin refuses to hear them. In fact, he chains them up as prisoners. (This should look up, but this one needs to rest a bit. Andrej is supposed to end up one of Odin's ulvhedin, leading an army of Vikings alongside the army of Scots and army of Valkyries.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1206</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-07-17 17:11:03]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-07-17 15:11:03]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[smaty]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>WIP Blog Tour</title>
		<link>http://mariehogebrandt.se/writers-block/wip-blog-tour/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 15:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariehogebrandt.se/?page_id=1224</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I ended up talking a bit extra with the awesome <a href="https://twitter.com/Ofoust">Olivia Foust</a>, one of many writerly tweeps I talk to on an irregular basis. For whatever reason we eventually ended up on her recent partaking in a <a href="http://ofoustwritesalot.blogspot.se/2014/09/wip-work-in-progress-blog-your.html">WIP Blog Tour</a>. She hadn't nominated anyone, so suggested that if I was interested, she would.</p>

<p>I agreed, so here's my contribution. I'm planning on nominating/linking to four of my other awesome tweeps, though I see no reason to pressure them if they are not interested in actually taking part (or, for that matter, have already done it). They're still awesome.</p>

<h2>My workspace</h2>

<p><img src="http://mariehogebrandt.se//assets/media/20140929_164324-1024x768.jpg" alt="Laptop with paper mug of coffee" width="940" height="705" class="alignright size-large wp-image-1226" /></p>

<p>That picture's taken on the train, showing Scrivener with this manuscript open, in particular at Chapter 4 (Unexpected Allies). The mug is a latte, and the yellow block is the cellphone I'm surfing via.</p>

<h2>Rules</h2>

<ul>
<li>Link the person who nominated you</li>
<li>Share a bit about your WIP</li>
<li>Share the first sentence of your first 3 chapters</li>
<li>Nominate 4 people to do the same</li>
</ul>

<h2>Maw of Eternal Darkness</h2>

<p>I have several WIPs, but decided to go with the one that I have the most written on. It's Epic Fantasy (I also call it Young Adult, but I've had people claim it doesn't feel that way, so I will leave that up in the air), set in a world inspired by the Norse mythology, as well as other sources of medieval/pre-medieval cultures. It is meant to be fantastic, and even in places have a sense of whimsy. To a large extent it follows the tropes of classic Swedish fairy tales such as <em>Prince Hat Underground</em>.</p>

<p>Originally it started as a small free-writing sketch that promised eroticism, with a barbarian kidnapping a princess from a tower. In the free-writing, the princess turned out to be chained to the wall, which intrigued me. After a while I wanted to get away from the normal tropes, so decided to make the barbarian female, but in the first version it ended coming off as transphobic (at least in my eyes), so I rewrote it.</p>

<p>In the current version, Lynessa is a princess in a somewhat English-esque kingdom called Keer. She is kidnapped by the Wild Hunt and taken to their keep of ice to be their Jarlswoman, the wife of the Jarl (think King) Vanlandi. Among the Northerners clans, gender is decided on the say-so of the spirits, not any physical characteristics, which confuses Lynessa as her supposed-husband is (per her) a woman.</p>

<p>When the Sun-Child (who is carried across the heavens by the Rider) is swallowed by the wolf hunting them, the young Jarl Vanlandi takes it on himself to recover the sun. The spirits--as interpreted by the Vala (Seer)--demand that Lynessa accompany him. Through their adventures, the damsel-y princess finds a strength within she would never have imagined.</p>

<p>My intentions are to post the first act--chapter by chapter, as I revise it to draft 2--on <a href="http://www.wattpad.com/story/21240656-maw-of-endless-darkness">Wattpad</a>, and once it's finished decide whether I will go Indie publishing, or court an agent/publisher.</p>

<h3>Chapter 1: The Princess in the Tower</h3>

<p>The snow-tinged wind howled outside Lynessa’s tower, rattling the stained glass windows, demanding to be let in.</p>

<h3>Chapter 2: The Wild Hunt</h3>

<p>The horse--white as curdled milk--whinnied.</p>

<h3>Chapter 3: Nothing is normal</h3>

<p>In the morning, Lynessa woke up in an unfamiliar bed.</p>

<h3>Teaser</h3>

<p>And here's the final bit of the final scene of the second act (1st draft, but the action/scene is the same).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Still in her own thoughts she walked through the courtyard, weaving between the stalls. Slowly she became aware of the voices and pointing. When she glanced up her eyes widened. The Vala, sprinting with her skirts gathered, grabbed her arm.</p>
  
  <p>“We need to get inside!” She gasped into her ear. “Come, child.”</p>
  
  <p>Lynessa followed the seer, stumbling as she stared back and up.</p>
  
  <p>And then, there was darkness.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>Nominees</h2>

<p>To re-iterate: Though I would love to see a WIP post from these lovely ladies, it is entirely up to them and how much time they have.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://theresolutionthebook.wordpress.com/">H.M. Brooks</a> -- Friend and sprinter, we've known each other ... since NaNo last year?</li>
<li><a href="http://caitreynolds.com/">Cait Reynolds</a> -- Also known as Fiona Blackthorne, she writes hot erotica with interesting storylines. Oh, and we word sprint =)</li>
<li><a href="http://theshadowsanctuary.wordpress.com/">Katherine Lampe</a> -- Witches and hot Scottish men, oh my! Katherine and I learned to know each other through the below nominee (She's already done this, but she still rocks, so my nomination stands)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.betterthanbullets.com/">Angelina Williamson</a> -- Another good friend on Twitter. No idea how we learned to know each other, but I enjoy talking with her</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1224</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2014-09-29 17:05:17]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-09-29 15:05:17]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[wip-blog-tour]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>1084</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_subtitle]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_username]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f49f7f486]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_number_of_images]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f4ae7f487]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_show_gallery]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[field_51b0f5971a206]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.w3-edge.com/products/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Minified using disk (wp-admin)
Database Caching using disk (Request-wide wp-admin)

 Served from: mariehogebrandt.se @ 2017-03-17 14:09:43 by W3 Total Cache -->